■
本字幕由 YYeTs人人影视 修正调整
欢迎爱好者加入我们 www.YYeTs.com
■
字幕来源: CHD     后期:beenoera
罗马  三年半前
嗨
Hi.
你还好吧? 糟透了
- How'd it go? - Lousy.
一年前  我只要一天就能把车卖掉
Got a '63 Thunderbird I would've sold in a day a year ago.
现在他们只想看照片
Now they just wanna look at the pictures.
你好香哦
You smell nice.
你好吗?
How was your day?
好得不得了
It was great.
宝格丽珠宝窃案有重大突破
We had a big breakthrough in the Bulgari case.
真的吗?
Really?
我们找到一个靴印
We found a boot print.
很清晰的靴印
A really good one.
左靴的鞋跟磨损得很严重
The left heel was worn way down.
很有用的线索
That's a good lead.
是啊!
I know.
我们也找到一根毛发
We found a hair.
一根毛发  真厉害
A hair, wow.
已经送去化验了
It's at the lab.
明天中午就会验出窃贼的DNA...
So hopefully by noon tomorrow we'll find out his DNA...
知道他用什么护发乳...
...what kind of conditioner he uses, if he streaks his hair...
或是他有没有头皮屑  很神奇吧?
...if he has dandruff, everything. Isn't that amazing?
是啊
That is amazing.
局里的男人真有一套
You know, having those extra men really paid off.
你也不要妄自菲薄
Oh, you're just being modest.
你上不上床?
Are you coming to bed, baby?
我去冲个澡  我不吵你睡觉
I'm just gonna have a shower. Don't let me keep you up.
十 二 罗 汉
康乃狄克州  新港市
三周半前
-早安 　-早安
- Good morning. - Good morning.
-请问贵姓大名?  -狄亚兹  米嘉・狄亚兹
- And you are Mr...? - Diaz. Miguel Diaz.
-您是来开...  -简易员工退休金帐户
- And you're here to open a...? - A SEP retirement account.
太好了  上面写您退休了
Terrific. Oh, it says here you're already retired.
-没错 　-请问您从事哪一行?
- I am. - What was your occupation?
我是高中篮球教练
I was a high school basketball coach.
您一定赚了不少钱
You must have done very well for yourself.
-你叫什么名字?   -克雷
- What's your name? - Greg.
我问你哦  这儿有保险箱吗?
Greg. Let me ask you something. Do you have safe-deposit boxes here?
有  就在金库里头
Yes, they're housed in our vault.
-这间银行有金库?   -它有一百年的历史
- In your vault? - It's over 100 years old.
当然  我们加装了最先进的防盗系统
Of course, we've made some state-of-the-art upgrades since then.
我曾经在金库里遇到银行抢案
You know, I was once in a vault while it was being robbed.
那一定是个很难忘的经验
That must have been quite an experience.
是啊
Yeah.
这颜色太深了
That's too oxblood.
你们从事哪一行?
What do y'all do?
我跟我先生吗?
My husband and I?
他退休了  才刚退休
Well, he's retired. Just retired.
挺好的
It's great. It's...
我在艺廊上过班  而且...
And I did work at an art gallery.
我热爱艺术  也很爱画画
And, you know, I love art, obviously, and paint and...
棕色太多了  抱歉  你不介意吧?
That's too brown. I'm sorry. Do you mind if I...?
-反正是你的油漆 　-谢谢
- Hey, it's your paint. - Okay. Thank you.
请问您要买什么?
May I show you something specific?
我在找送老婆的礼物
Well, I was looking for something for my wife.
是什么特别的日子吗?
What is it, a special occasion?
我们第二次的结婚三周年纪念
It's our second third anniversary.
对不起  狄亚兹太太  我们正提到你
Excuse me. Hello, Mrs. Diaz, we were just talking about you.
-银行的事办得如何?   -小意思
- How'd it go at the bank? - It was easy.
我是说很顺利
I mean great.
不  你是说小意思
No, you mean easy.
怎么了?
What?
你在结婚纪念日去探路?
You're doing recon work on our anniversary?
-泰丝 　 -我问你...
- Tess. - Let me ask you this:
-你人在哪儿?   -探一间珠宝店的路
- Where are you now? - Casing a jewelry store.
你这样要怎么当好人?  你自己说要改邪归正的
That's an interesting way to ease back into society, which was your idea.
-我还要继续粉刷房子吗?  - 听好...
- Should I stop painting now? - Listen.
说点正事  我找不到好馆子
Let's talk about something important. I can't find a restaurant for tonight.
-那就在家吃吧 　-是吗?
- Well, we'll stay in. - Really?
-好  我烧菜 　-我动手  你动口
- Great. I'll cook. - No, I'll cook. You talk.
你要我动口
You want me to talk?
跟你让浪漫情话?那鲜花是用来干嘛?
Words and everything? That's what they make flowers for, you know.
-不好了  丹尼 　-怎么了?
- Oh, no, Danny. - What is it?
泰丝?
Tess...
怎么了?
...what's wrong?
地下室进水了  热水炉熄火了
There's water in the basement and the pilot light is out.
挂电话
Hang up!
你好  泰丝
Hello, Tess.
他在哪里?
Where is he, Tess?
狄亚兹先生
Where is...
在哪里?
...Mr. Diaz?
我要讨回来
I want it back, Tess.
我要把钱全都讨回来
I want it all back.
-保险公司已经全都赔给你了 　-我要我的钱
- You got it all from the insurance company. - I want my money back.
你老公跟他十个朋友偷的钱
The money that your husband and his 10 friends stole from me.
还要加利息  一亿六千万美元
With interest. A hundred and sixty million dollars over three years.
三年多的利息可是不少钱
That's a lot of vig.
我全都要讨回来
And I want it all back.
他有两个星期的时间
He's got two weeks.
你找不到他们的
You'll never find them.
他们比你聪明多了
They're way too smart for you.
是啊
Right.
但是这世上并不是只有我...
You know, as it turns out...
在找这群"欧逊的十一大盗"
...I'm not the only person in the world looking for Ocean's 11.
好吧
All right.
犹他州
普罗沃
我知道新郎通常不需致词  但是...
I'm the groom, and I'm not supposed to say anything, but... Make a speech.
我不管那些繁文缛节  我要感谢我的家人
But I don't care what the rules are, because I really wanna thank my family.
我爸妈  盖瑞叔和葛丝婶
My mom and dad, my Uncle Gary and Aunt Grace.
泰德叔和赛莉丝婶
Uncle Ted, Aunt Celeste...
他们的小孩  丹尼丝和洁西卡
...and their children, Denise and Jessica.
汤姆牧师和牧师娘海伦  我的邻居约翰...
Bishop Tom and his wife, Helen, my neighbor John...
和他新女友谭雅
...and his new girlfriend, Tanya.
还有车厂的同事波波  怪头...
And all the guys at Lean Machine Inc., Bobo, Mullethead...
大山姆
...Big Sam.
还有祝福我们的...
And everyone else who's just been great...
每个亲朋好友  谢谢大家
...in welcoming Sara into the family. Thank you.
对不起  各位  我只想...
Excuse me, everybody. I'd just like to...
-起来 　-起来
- Get up. - Get up.
-起来 　-起来  起来
- Get up. - Get up. Get up.
走吧 　走吧
- Walk. - Walk.
我想说几句话  关于承诺...
I'd like to say a few words about commitment...
关于荣誉心
...about honor...
关于责任感
...about responsibility...
还有对终身伴侣坦承...
...about a very special someone and admitting to her...
起来  椅子拉出来
Get up. Pull the chair out.
在大家面前向她坦承...
Admitting to her in front of everybody...
她的婚礼...
...that her wedding...
还有到迪士尼乐园的蜜月旅行
...and that very special honeymoon trip to Epcot Center...
必须要延期举行
...will have to be postponed.
那个摄影师?他只是朋友  你也见过他
The photographer. Jesus, he's just a friend. You met him at The Mint, remember?
佛罗里达州
迈阿密
当然
Well, of course I am.
拜托  坐经济舱很没面子
You don't expect me to embarrass myself by flying commercial?
你要我省钱?
On a budget? On a budget?
有没有搞错?谁叫你打不进中国的手机市场
Who was the only person who couldn't get in on the Chinese cell-phone market?
你不是很有办法吗?搞什么啊?
You, with all your connections. What was that?
他看起来人很好  你也知道男人都不把我当朋友
He seemed really nice. And you know it's hard for guys to be friends with me.
我每次认识新朋友  你就发神经
And you do this every time that I meet someone new.
你知道吗?这真的很烦耶
And you know what? It's getting really boring.
女孩子的摄影师一定会曝光
法兰克指甲美容院
没有人听过我朋友佛瑞德・凯利
You think it's a accident no one know about Fred "Bud" Kelly?
新泽西州
东橘市
这并不是意外  这只有一个原因
Ain't no accident. There's one explanation...
你们这些美女一定知道
...and you ladies know exactly what it is.
让我告诉你们
I'm gonna tell you what it is.
这是个大阴谋  大诡计
Conspiracy, collusion, complicity. That's all it is.
我就跟你们一一细说我老友佛瑞德的丰功伟业
Let me break it down like a fraction for you about my man Fred "Bud" Kelly.
十世纪初  他在新斯科细亚...
Fred "Bud" Kelly made skates out of whiskey bottles...
在他叔叔的农场里用威士忌酒瓶做冰刀
...at his uncle's farm in the early 1900s. That was over there in Nova Scotia.
我再跟你们说他从来没赢过史丹利杯
I'm gonna tell you something else. You never seen his name on the Stanley Cup.
为什么?因为臭白人...
You know why that is? Because that son of a bitch Jim Crow...
把他从历史上除名
...took his name off the history books. You kind of...
好像我每次碰到你  你都用种族歧视这一招
Seems like every time I see you, you're playing the race card, Frank.
为什么?
Now, why is that?
请你放开我的脚
You can let go of my feet now.
英国  伦敦
- 你不觉得这很烦吗?   -我... 当然烦
- This don't bother you? - Of course it bothers me, mate.
-你他妈的要我怎么办?  -真烦人
- What the do you want me to do? - Well, it's up.
都听不到歌词了
You can't hear none of the lyrics.
那么多消音把节奏都搞乱了
You can't get with the beat with all them                      bleeps in it.
你想他妈的当红歌星就得这么搞
You want a single on the radio, it's what you have to do.
狗屁  这太扯了
Well, it's, isn't it? Totally!
没错  你他妈的
right, it's .
那是什么屁音乐?
What the is that?
有人在二号录音间
Somebody must be in 2.
见鬼
Oh, !
伊利诺州
芝加哥
你没找上我老爸吧?
And you haven't contacted my father about any of this?
你没有必要把我爸妈拖下水
Because, really, I don't think there's any reason to involve him or my mom.
我只针对你  莱纳斯
It's all on you, Linus.
好  那就好
Okay. Good.
-我在这儿有很多人脉...   -给我下车
- Good. Because I have a whole network... - Get out of my car.
谢谢你
Thank you.
-布鲁先生?  -是的
- Mr. Bloom? - Yes.
您的信用卡有点问题
There appears to be a slight problem with your card.
纽约州
东汉普顿
好  用这个吧
Oh, well, yes. Here.
这张卡也不能刷
I'm afraid not, sir.
为什么?
Why?
您的财务经理说您会理解
Your business manager said you would understand.
陶德这么说吗?
Todd said I would understand?
不  是班奈狄先生
No, Mr. Benedict.
班奈狄先生...
Mr. Benedict. Mr...
是的
Oh, yes.
这是一位老朋友的恶作剧
An old friend, a practical joker.
请转告班奈狄先生  说他赢了
Tell Mr. Benedict he's won this round, yes.
泰瑞班奈狄
Terry Benedict.
泰瑞真行
Old Terry.
她一直盯着我
She's looking at me from across the room.
她一定看上我了  我看得出来
And she's crazy about me, I can tell...
路易斯安那州
纽奥良
因为她含情脉脉地看着我
...because she's been staring at me all night. So suddenly...
于是我突然站起来抱住她
...I just go up to her, and I grab her.
当我紧紧地抱着她
And I've got her really close to me...
她的眼睛在向我放电
...and her eyes are all fiery.
顿时天雷...
And my eyes are fiery.
勾动地火
And it's like... It's electric.
我跟她说:"老妈"
And I say to her, "Mom...
我居然说老妈
Mother... "
什么?
What?
谢谢你让我表演完
Thanks for letting me finish.
没办法
What can I say?
谁叫你这么会搞笑
You're a funny guy.
内华达州
拉斯维加斯
我朋友罗斯  我很担心他
Oh, yeah. My friend Rusty. I'm worried about him.
他在洛杉矶有家饭店
He owns this hotel in Los Angeles...
赔了不少钱  他忙得不行
...losing a lot of money, and he's got no life.
他人很好  只是很不会赚钱
He's a nice, bright kid, but he's beating his brains out.
你可以用念力传话给他吗?
Do you think I could send something through you, like, a message to him?
我是在看你的手相耶
I read your palm, not his.
你有这本事就能赚人钱  我的身体没毛病吧?
Somebody who could do that could do very well. Anything on my health?
-我的腰怪怪的 　-请出去
- My hips are bothering me. - Please.
你算不出我会有这种衰运吗?
This? You couldn't see this?
加州
西好莱坞
-他不肯开门 　-让我来  我认识他
- I tried knocking, he won't open. - I'll handle it. I know him.
拜托  你们是智障吗?
Jesus Christ, are you people retarded?
-门外写着"请勿打扰"   -是我
- It says, "Do not disturb"! - It's me.
嗨
Hey.
进来吧
Come on in.
托佛  别学人家乱砸房间嘛
Jeez, Topher, you didn't have to go all Frankie Muniz on me.
抱歉  我知道这是你的饭店
I'm sorry. Rust, look, I know this is your joint.
我只是
I just...
我交了一个女朋友
There's this girl.
我很爱她
I love her, man.
不过  她快把我逼疯了
I love her, but she is driving me crazy!
我不能睡觉  不能工作
I can't sleep. I can't work.
节目也停掉了  那部新片我也演砸了
I quit the show. I totally phoned in that Dennis Quaid movie.
-我真的是...   -喂?
- I mean, it's like... - Hello?
这烂喀巴拉手环根本没用
God, it's almost like this Kabbalah crap doesn't even work!
罗斯  电话
Rusty, call for you.
老兄  别走
Dude, don't leave.
-喂?  -我要给罗伯莱恩留言
- Yeah? - I have a message for Robert Charles Ryan...
他很快会失去史坦德饭店
...soon to be ex-owner of the Standard Hotel.
-我就是 　-上次你挂我电话...
- You got him. - Last time we spoke, you hung up on me.
谁叫你骂脏话  我不爽听
You used some nasty words. I got sensitive ears.
我那天是有点激动
I admit I was a little emotional that evening.
你常想到那件事  对吧?
Think about that night a lot, don't you?
你竟然还先打电话来  我以为我死定了
I thought I'd be dead before I heard the sound that killed me.
有人叫我节制一点  要不然你哪天早上出门
I've been asked to show restraint. Otherwise, you would've gone out...
坐上你的名贵轿车  用车钥匙启动引擎...
...to your favorite car of all the 17 you own, and as soon as you turned on the ignition...
你有两个礼拜
You got two weeks.
第一个星期四  只剩十三天
你老婆说他称我们为"欧逊的十一大盗"
Now, you told me that your wife said that he called it Ocean's 11.
搞什么?我可是个体户
Now, who decided that? I'm a private contractor.
大家都出了力  不是你的功劳
It was a collaboration. That moniker is insulting.
对  大家分工合作
It was one job we did together.
怎么会变成你一个人挂名?这有点过分
I don't know where this proprietary stance comes from. It seems possessive.
也许是因为这是丹尼的点子
One could make the argument that because it was Danny's idea...
等一下  每个人都有专长
Hang on a minute. We all had our own areas of expertise.
没有我们  你连屁都没有
I mean, without us, it don't leave your head, mate.
这很伤人
It just hurts, you know, because...
因为我以为大家说好了  叫它是"赌城那一票"
...it seemed we all agreed to call it "the Benedict job. "
当时我们都是这么叫的
That's what we called it when we were doing it.
你不能随便改名字
If you wanted to call it something else...
等等  有麻烦都找谁搞定?
When you have a problem, who do you go to?
-罗斯 　-罗斯
- Rusty. - Rusty.
谢了  莱纳斯  言归正传吧
Thanks. Let's get back on the topic.
每个人分的钱加上利息...
Based on what we stole, plus interest...
是多少? 一千七百三十四万
...how much does everybody owe? - $ 17.34 million.
但是班奈狄绝不会给我们优惠利率
Assuming Benedict gives us prime plus one, which I doubt.
抓一千九百万比较保险
Figure 19 to be safe.
好  有谁还得起一千九百万吗?
Okay, 19 each. Anybody got that?
干嘛?难道股市那么深奥
What, you think the stock market's some great mystery...
真的有那么难懂吗?你们都没看到征兆吗?
...beyond the realm of human understanding? Didn't you see the signs?
我就有看到
I saw the signs.
大家各缺多少?
How much is everybody short?
你缺多少?
How much you short?
一千四百万
Fourteen. Fourteen.
-你花到剩五百万?  -是啊  你要跟我说教吗?
- All but 5 million? - Yeah. You gonna start with me?
自己创业很不容易的
You don't know what it's like to create something from scratch.
-我只缺七百万 　-八百万
- Well, with interest, I'm short 7. - Eight.
我花了一百万栽培新人
I spent about a million, mostly on talent development.
我也缺七百万  利息真是要人命
That makes it 7 for me. Boy, the interest just kills you.
-我缺九百万 　-利息有多少?
- I'm light 9. - What's the interest?
-六百万 　-那我只缺六百万
- About 6. - Then I owe 6.
-怎么会?   -什么?
- How? - What?
我都住在父母家里
I've been staying at my parents'.
我缺两千五百万
I owe 25.
饭店赔惨了
Hotels, man.
索尔?
Saul?
我钱还没花完  但很快就会了
I haven't spent it all, but I will.
别把我算在内
I'm out, fellas.
我是个老人  不得不承认  我干不动了
As ranking old-timer, I gotta say, I just can't do it.
我这把年纪总可以自私点吧
At my age, I think I earned the right to be selfish.
谢谢各位给我这个机会  你们都是高手  但是...
I wanna thank you all for the wonderful opportunity. You're all aces in my book.
我打算在死前... 把每一分钱花光
But I want the last check I write to bounce.
索尔  你在耍我们吗?
Saul, you having a laugh?
索尔
Saul.
-我可以替索尔还钱 　-你不必这么做
- I can handle Saul's share. - You don't have to.
你们都挂了  我找谁聊天?
Who would I talk to if you were all dead?
有道理  我欠一千万  小颜呢?
That's a good point. All right, I owe 10. Amazing?
不过你那栋豪宅超豪华的
Yeah, but it's a nice place.
-加起来一共是...   -差不多九千七百万
- So that comes to...? - Ninety-seven, give or take.
凭他自已是找不到我们的
He didn't find us on his own.
-一定有人帮忙 　-另一个小偷
- Someone helped him. - Another thief.
我们的熟人不会违反第一条行规
Nobody we know would violate rule number one.
咱们得干一票  很大的一票
What we do know is we need a job. We need a high-paying job.
咱们在美国太惹人注意了
We're too hot to work anywhere in this country.
-那就出国 　-下十五点钟的班机
- So we go abroad. How about we go...? - We're on the 5:00.
好  去哪儿?
Good. Where are we going?
-阿姆斯特丹 　-就这么办吧
- Amsterdam. - Amsterdam it is.
-时间紧迫  出发吧 　-我没去过阿姆斯特丹
- Clock's running. Let's go. - Never been to Amsterdam.
听说德国妞很辣
I hear German girls are really hot.
罗斯
Rusty.
-阿姆斯特丹?  -是的
- Amsterdam? - Yeah.
别告诉丹尼
Don't tell Danny.
罗斯
Hey, Rusty. Rusty.
不好意思
Sorry, sorry. Hey.
搞什么?怎么了?
What are you doing? What's wrong with you?
-没什么?  -什么?
- Nothing. - What?
-我能不能...   -什么?
- Can I...? Can I...? - What?
-我想跟你聊聊 　-怎么了?
- Just for a second, can I talk to you? - What's wrong?
我只是...
I just... I don't know.
现在谈这件事也许不太好
This might not be the perfect time or whatever to talk about it.
-好吧 　-我只是在想...
- Okay. - I've been thinking.
我一直在用功
I've been doing my homework.
这次我很想...
And I'd really like...
扮演比较有份量的角色
...to play a more central role this time around.
-我觉得我...
- Right. - I feel like I've...
-是哦我都准备好了
- Right. - I'm ready for that, and I...
是哦 　我都准备好了
Way overdue.
我想跟你们一起去谈生意  帮忙出主意
I was wondering if I could come to the meeting and help you guys negotiate.
好吧  只是跟松井开个会
Okay. It's just a sit-down with Matsui.
这家伙讲话不太好懂
He's got his own language, this guy.
上次我仔细观察过你跟丹尼  我学到很多
I watched you and Danny really closely last time around. I learned a ton.
我专业的意见是  你还不行
Linus, in my professional opinion, you're not ready.
-好吧  是啦 　-不过... 可是...
- Okay. Yeah, I mean... - But... But... But...
如果你觉得有把握
...if you're convinced you are ready...
我可以说服丹尼让你跟去
...I can speak with Danny. We can make this happen.
不过你得有把握
But you gotta be sure.
-你没有把握?   -不  我有
- Not sure? - No, I am.
-你肯定?   -不过要是有问题...
- You're sure? - But if I had a question, I could...
-你可以来找我 　-对
- You would call me? - Right. Okay.
随时都行
Any time.
-好啊 　-好啊
- Okay. - Okay.
-好了 　-好  太好了  谢谢你
- All right. - Okay. Awesome. Thank you.
好
Yeah.
我差点就决定不来找你
I almost wasn't gonna come over and say anything.
我就可以继续睡大觉
Then I'd still be sleeping.
-谢了  小伙子 　-好
- Thanks, buddy. - Yeah.
阿 姆 斯 特 丹
-谁呀?   -莱纳斯
- Who's there? - Li... It's...
-什么?   -莱纳斯
- What? - It's Linus.
罗斯人呢?
Is Rusty here? Rusty...?
-罗斯在哪儿?   -不知道
- Do you know where Rusty is? - No.
你见过松井吗?
So have you met Matsui?
说真的  你觉得我...
Seriously, what do you think of me...
有当一哥的潜力吗?
...you know, in terms of just leadership potential?
你得忘了咱们不能工作
The fact that we're unemployable shouldn't enter your mind.
第一个星期六
只剩十一天
不然  你只会浪费你的时间
Otherwise, you're wasting time.
千万别提到班奈狄
Don't mention Benedict unless he does first.
他先提起的话  就坦白地说出来
And if he does, tell him everything.
说重点  别忘了我说的那件事
Right. Stay on point. And don't forget the other thing I told you.
-什么事?   -认真听话
- What? - About listening.
别紧张  记住  接不到这一票就死定了
Relax. Remember, if we don't get this job, we're dead.
我昨天一直在找你
Rusty, I tried calling you all yesterday.
最后她把酒杯摔在托盘上说:
So finally, she slams her vodka tonic down on the tray and says:
"怪不得我最近觉得这么热"
"Hey, maybe that's why I've been feeling so warm recently. "
好啊
Yeah.
-谈正事吧 　-谈正事
- So to business? - To business.
有一位皮肤科医生...
A doctor who specializes in skin diseases...
会梦到他在电视前面睡着
...will dream he has fallen asleep in front of the television.
然后在电视前面醒来
Later, he will wake up in front of the television...
而不记得他做的梦
...but not remember his dream.
你同意吗?
Would you agree?
如果住在赤道的动物够厚道...
If all the animals along the equator were capable of flattery...
就会把感恩节和万圣节
...then Thanksgiving and Halloween...
放在同一天
...would fall on the same date.
是啊
Yeah. Hey.
我四岁时...
When I was 4 years old...
看到我妈用茶壶保温袋  杀死一只蜘蛛
...I watched my mother kill a spider with a tea cozy.
多年后  我才发现那不是蜘蛛
Years later, I realized it was not a spider.
而是我的哈洛叔
It was my Uncle Harold.
让阳光照射我的睑颊
Oh, let the sun beat down upon my face
让星辰进入我的梦中
Stars to fill my dreams
我是一名时空的旅客
I am a traveler in both time and space
重返我曾去过的地方
To be where I have been
他怎样?没事吧?
Is he all right? Are we all right?
《喀什米尔》的歌词? 你这是在帮倒忙
- "Kashmir"? - Is that your idea of making a contribution?
-我们都还没谈条件 　-你差点就把这一票搞砸
- We hadn't even started yet. - We were this close to losing that.
我完全被搞糊涂了  我到底说了些什么?
Okay, I don't even understand what happened in there. What did I say?
-你骂他侄女是妓女 　-还是廉价妓女
- You called his niece a whore. - A cheap one.
-她才七岁 　-而且还染上病...
- She's 7. - Confined to bed with a case of...
-别跟他说了 　-没错  对不起
- No, don't tell him about it. - I'm sorry.
这代表什么?
Okay. So, what does this mean?
你要乖乖待在这儿
It means you stay here.
目标是范德沃特一个有钱的神秘客
The mark's name is van der Woude. A semi-known, wealthy recluse.
多年来他都自称是古董商  却没卖过古董
He claims to sell antiques, but hasn't actually sold one.
他的店就是他家  没人进去过
His store is his privately owned home, which no one ever enters.
别被这个怪人给骗了
But don't let van der Woude's eccentricity fool you.
他的房子戒备森严
The house is extremely well-protected.
-我们要偷什么?   -一份文件
- What are we after? - It's a document.
一份很珍贵的古老文件
It's a very old, very valuable document.
-什么文件?   -一张股票
- Yeah, what is it? - A stock certificate.
史上第一家公司的第一张股票
The first one ever issued from the first corporation on the planet.
荷属东印度公司
Dutch East India Trading Company.
-绝无仅有 　 -能赚多少钱?
- The only one of its kind. - What's the take?
两百五十万欧元?
2.5 million euro.
每个人吗?
Wait. Each?
-不是 　-这是谁谈的条件?
- No. - Who negotiated this?
-对很多人来说  这可是一大笔钱 　-你疯了?
- That's a lot of money to a lot of people. - Are you out of your mind?
这样要等到几时才能把钱还清?
If we do one job a week at that rate, we won't pay Benedict off until...
-2005年9月 　-老天爷
- September 2005. - Jesus Christ, Danny.
我知道  但目前只有这一票
I hear you, but it's what's available.
干完这一票
After we pull this job off...
松井会安排更大的一票
...Matsui's gonna throw us another. It's gonna pay 10 times this one.
-至少能让我们有机会延长期限 　-你想啦
- Which will buy an extension from Benedict. - You hope.
我是很想呀  松井把密码给了我们
I hope. Now, the good news is that Matsui gave us the system's master code.
-那还在等什么?  -等范德沃特出门
- So, what are we waiting for? - Van der Woude.
-坏消息就是这个了 　-他从不出门
- That's the bad news. - He never leaves.
-他有人群恐惧症 　-他没出过家门?
- He's agoraphobic. - He's never been out of his house?
-搬进去十年都没有 　-他不需要新鲜空气?
- Not in 10 years since he moved in. - Does he believe in fresh air?
-他偶尔会打开二楼窗户 　-什么意思?
- He opens his window. - What does that mean?
-那就是下手的最好时机 　-他会打开窗户
- Best time of arrival. - Means he opens his window.
他每晚一点半都会吃安眠药  听贝多芬交响曲
Every night at 1:30 he takes an Ambien, puts on Beethoven's Third.
听到第四乐章就不醒人事  咱们半夜三点进去
By the fourth movement, he's out like a light. So we go in at 3 a. m.
可以用电话侵入保安系统吗?
Okay, can we tap into the system from the phone lines?
不行  那是密闭回路系统
It's a closed-loop system with two servers
锁在他床头边的钛合金保险箱
locked in titanium cases next to his bed.
-无法侵入电脑系统 　-很简单
- So hacking in is out. - Look at this.
假扮成电信局员工爬到二楼
Telephone-repair truck, basket up to the second floor.
从窗口潜进去  输入密码就搞定
Telescoping rod through the window, tap out the freak's code.
-真够蠢  那是单行道 　-真够蠢?
- Dumb idea. One lane, one-way streets. - Dumb idea.
违规停车会招来警察
All right? Any stoppage will bring cops.
房子外面有五个摄影机
The outside is covered by five surveillance cameras.
保安公司24小时监控
Monitored 24 hours a day by a security company.
五个监看摄影机?
He's got five exterior cameras?
-这家伙真是个怪胎 　-超级大怪胎
- This guy is a freak. - Super freak.
从屋顶爬进去呢?
What about through the roof?
-两个摄影机和压力感测器 　-还有雷射防盗网
- Two more cameras, pressure sensors... - A laser net over the trap door...
-用火把那怪胎逼出来 　-好啊
- Smoke the freak out. - Yeah.
-把那怪胎逼出来 　-嘿!
- Smoke the freak out. - Hey!
-干嘛?   -能不能不要用那字眼?
- What? - Do we have to use that term?
-什么字眼?   -怪胎
- What term? - "Freak. "
国际心理健康学会估计  百分之五点六的成人...
The National Institute of Mental Health estimates 5.6 percent of adults...
-有惧高症 　-是人群恐惧症
...develop "agraphoriaphobia. " - Agoraphobia.
随便啦  我只是说...
Whatever. I'm just saying, I mean, do we...?
我们的组织不该给别人贴标签
We don't need to be an organization that labels people.
我们几时变成组织了?
Oh, now we're an organization?
你们会说狄更生是怪胎吗?
You'd call Emily Dickinson a freak?
-你在主持慈善晚会吗?   -狄更生是什么人?
- Are you hosting a telethon? - Who's Emily Dickinson?
咱们去偷一个残障人士
Am I the only one who feels funny about stealing from a...?
难道只有我觉得良心不安吗?
You know, a handicapped guy?
-我才不在乎 　-是啊  只有你
- Well, I don't care. - Hell, yeah.
我对别的事会良心不安
I feel funny about other things.
好吧
Cool.
可是呢...
But...
-什么?   -可是...
- Yeah? - But...
-是的 　-什么?
- Right. - What?
-没错  用妹妹背洋娃娃那招 　-我能弄到装备
- Ahab with a piggyback. Livingston? - I can get anything.
-那就好办了 　-妹妹背洋娃娃?
- It's done. - Ahab with what?
-大伙儿 　-你在瞎扯  根本没这一招
- Boys. - You're making that up. That's...
妹妹背洋娃娃是你瞎掰的吧?
That whole "Ahab with a piggyback," that's not real?
-法兰克  快点出来 　-你蹲厕所时...
- Let me in. - How do you think it feels...
喜欢别人催你吗? 他再不出来...
...when someone bangs on the door? - I gotta go to the toilet.
我就要拉在你身上  快出来
Otherwise, I'm gonna shit on your feet. Come on.
第一个星期天  只剩十天
给我看看说明书
Show me them specs.
我十二岁就开饭店  大小事你都管是不行的
I've been doing this since I'm 12 years old. You're micromanaging.
你得找人替你打理  不然就没自己的生活
You gotta find people you can delegate to. Otherwise, you'll never have a life.
我不要自己的生活  我只要饭店正常运作
I don't want a life. I want the hotel to run like a hotel should.
鲁本
Reuben.
喂?
Yeah.
太好了
Great.
-好  很好 　-也许吧
- Okay. Good. - Maybe.
这太好了
Fantastic.
记得《黑帮龙虎斗》约翰特托罗跪地求饶那一幕吗?
Remember in Miller's Crossing where Turturro begs for his life?
记得:"发发好心吧! "
Sure. "Look into your heart. "
我每次看都会哭
I cry every time.
怎么了?
What?
那栋房子滴水不漏
We have no line of sight.
唯一的缺口是二楼窗户  可是差了三英寸
Our only possibility, the window. We're three inches too high.
连拜许这神枪手也瞄不准
There's no clear shot, even with Basher.
在现实世界  这是不可能的任务
In the physical universe we occupy, it cannot be done.
宝格丽珠宝窃案那家伙呢?
What about the guy from the Bulgari job?
-奈格  我跟他谈过 　-有用吗?
- Nagel. Spoke with him. - Anything?
他的方法都不管用
Lot of ideas, none of them any good.
他在研发全新虚拟影像技术
He's pushing this new holographic technology.
很有意思  他能复制任何东西的立体影像
Really interesting stuff, though. He can reproduce anything 3-D.
九千七百万也能复制吗?
How about 97 million?
咱们死定了
We're forcing it.
没错  死定了
Yeah, we're forcing it.
-有个方法没想过 　-什么方法?
- You know what we haven't thought of? - What?
向警方自首
We turn ourselves in.
-班奈狄就拿我们没办法 　-没错
- What could Benedict do to us then? - There you go.
承认干下贝拉吉赌场窃案
Call the cops, tell them we did the Bellagio job.
蹲20年苦窑  让他拿我们没办法
They put us away for 20 years. That'd teach him.
我想泰丝一定会等我
I think Tess would stick around.
你穿囚衣很帅
You look great in jumpsuits.
嗨...
Hey...
-经营饭店好玩吗?   -不好玩
...how's the hotel business? - Sucks.
-新港市好玩吗?   -不好玩
- How's East Haven? - Sucks.
我不知道
I don't know.
我就是狗改不了吃屎
Can't turn my brain off, you know. It's me.
去哪儿就会想... 该怎么下手
We go into some place, and all I can do is see the angles.
这一行我干了一辈子  我就爱这样子
It's what I do. It's what I've always done. I love it.
我不知道
I don't know.
真的很难熬
Some sort of weird irony, you know?
泰丝老是看我心痒难搔
Tess watching me scratch and itch.
这年头  大家都疯了
Hey, listen. You know, the world's gone nuts and you're...
你想怎样? 那栋房子跟隔壁没有相连
- What'd you wanna do? - It's not attached to the adjacent buildings.
整栋房子? 只是抬高一丁点
- The whole house? - We're just raising it slightly.
舒曼64年在威尼斯干过  73年在伊斯坦堡干过
Schumann did it in '64 in Venice and '73 in Istanbul.
-他只有六个帮手 　-不可能抬起整栋房子
- He only had a crew of six. - We can't tilt a house.
-比萨斜塔就是这么干 　-没错  谢谢
- Did it with the Leaning Tower of Pizza. - Exactly, thank you.
-三百人花了两年才完工 　-共三十根梁柱
- It took 300 men over two years to do it. - There's 30 pylons.
先锯断  再用千斤顶抬高
We cut them, insert the jacks and crank away.
这是唯一和最好的计划
It's really our best plan, considering it's our only plan.
-要抬到多高?   -这是唯一的办法
- Crank for how long? - Like I said, it's our only plan.
第一个星期二  只剩八天
什么?
What?
好  等一下
Oh, oh, okay, hold on.
再下去看看
Try that.
我是五号  要动手了
Number five. I'm a go.
放长线钓大鱼的神偷  都过着正常生活
Master thieves who practice the long con live separate lives as civilians.
他们有正当职业和家庭
They have legitimate jobs and families...
使他们很难被抓到
...which make them extremely difficult to catch.
史上最伟大的神偷是
The greatest thief of all time was, without question...
盖斯伯勒马克  他不是1988年死于葡萄牙
...Gaspar LeMarc, who either died in Portugal in 1988...
就是1996年在香港去世  或许他仍活在人世
...or in Hong Kong in 1996, or he's still alive.
我们永远都无法确知  因为...
We may never know for certain, because LeMarc...
他没被抓过  也从来没曝光
...was never captured or photographed...
虽然他活跃了五十几年
...despite being active for over 50 years.
有很多人想当他的接班人
Though he left behind a slew of imitators...
当今唯一值得一提的高手
...only one is worth mentioning in the same breath as LeMarc:
就是被称为"夜狐"的神偷
The thief we know only as the Night Fox.
他总是在现场留下狐狸小玩偶
So named for the small onyx figurines he leaves behind to taunt us...
夜狐是我们的头号嫌犯
...the Night Fox must be considered our number-one priority.
他犯下的一连串惊人窃案
His string of high-profile crimes are an embarrassment to our branch...
让国际刑警颜面尽失
...to our entire profession.
我们需要比传统资源更有效的方法才能逮到像他这种神偷
We need more than traditional resources to pursue thieves like the Night Fox.
我们必须用他们的思考逻辑看出一件案子的蹊跷
We need to train ourselves to think the way they think, to see what they see.
我们也不能被任何事分心
And we should not allow ourselves to be distracted...
对不起  刚才有人爆窃范德沃特的家
I'm sorry. Someone just robbed the van der Woude house.
什么?
What?
伊莎贝  这次又要请你帮忙了
Hi, Isabel. Well, we could really use your help on this one.
希望现场没遭到破坏
I hope the scene hasn't been contaminated.
几时能跟范德沃特先生说话?
When can I speak to Mr. Van der Woude?
明天吧  他服了镇静剂
Probably tomorrow. He's heavily sedated.
想不透他们怎么解除警铃  也许是造成电线短路
We can't figure out how they disabled the alarm. Shorted it out somehow?
不可能  那会触动警铃  破坏系统线路
No, that would have triggered the system and damaged the circuits.
那我就不知道他们是怎么进来的了
Well, then. Then I don't know how they got in.
他们有密码  除了屋主  别人也有密码
They had the code. Someone other than the owner must have known it.
他发誓这是不可能的  保安密码是他亲自设定的
Impossible. Van der Woude programmed the last nine steps of the system.
设定后就没再出门
He set it and never left the house again.
密闭回路系统  钛合金保险箱
Closed loop. Redundant servers. Titanium encasement.
保安系统非常严密
It's not bad, actually.
谢谢
Yeah. Thanks.
我们认识吗?
Do we know each other?
-我昨天见过你 　-是吗?
- I think I saw you yesterday. - Oh, yeah?
你被警察追着跑
Yeah, you were being chased by the police.
我被警察追?不  不可能是我
Chasing me? No. I don't think so.
我很确定是你
I'm quite sure it was you.
那么警察真无能
Doesn't say much for the police.
我喜欢罗马  我很爱罗马
No, I love Rome. I love it.
不过  我有一个升迁机会
But there's an opening at work the level above me, and it's...
我想去阿姆斯特丹试试看
I was thinking I was gonna try out for it. It's in Amsterdam.
我妈在那儿有亲戚  很方便
My mother has family there, so it'd be... It'd be good.
他把整栋房子抬高了? 没错
- He lifted the whole house? - The whole house.
-整栋房子?  -对
- The entire house? - The entire house.
这叫做舒曼手法
It's called a Schumann Special...
以一个天才神偷舒曼命名
...named after this guy, a brilliant guy, Max Schumann.
他在1973年... 在伊斯坦堡又干过一次
Then he did it in Istanbul in 1973.
那是什么?
What is it?
十字弓射出来的洞
It's where the crossbow bolt hit.
十字弓?
The crossbow bolt?
他们从对面屋顶射入窗口
They fired from that rooftop through this open window.
从对面屋顶射入窗口?
With a crossbow bolt from that roof through that window?
-这难度太高了吧?  -这是不可能的任务
- That's a very difficult shot. - No, it is an impossible shot...
直到他们把房子抬高了
...until they raised the building.
检查梁枉  应该都被升高了
Check the pylons. They'll be elevated.
-你听过舒曼这名字吗?  -没有
- You know the name Max Schumann? - No.
-他们听过 　-谁?
- Well, they do. - Who?
那伙美国人
The Americans.
启动
慢着
Wait a minute.
派不上用场  何必带电钻?
Exactly. Why would they bring the drill if they weren't planning to use it?
-怎么了?   -天啊
- What? - Oh, God.
-什么事?   -我不知道
- What? - I don't know.
请按播放键
恭喜了  你是今晚第二个成功侵入的小偷
Congratulations. You are the second person to crack the van der Woude safe tonight.
欧逊先生  你就跟一大堆...
In arriving second, Mr. Ocean, you have joined a long line...
辛苦卖力的二流小偷一样赌上生命却只能沦为第二名
...of people who've worked hard and risked a great deal only to get somewhere second.
你不会记得这些人的名字  因为他们都默默无闻
You don't know these people by name, of course, because they enter oblivion.
你知道默默无闻这句成语吗?
You know this word, "oblivion"?
意思是被世人永远遗忘
It means to be totally forgotten by everyone forever.
你只是靠贝拉吉赌场那一票出名
And it's where you would be now if it weren't for the Bellagio heist.
这家伙怎么知道我们是谁?
How does this guy know who we are?
其实是我害你们大老远跑来这儿
In a way, I'm responsible for you coming to Amsterdam in the first place.
我请松井找你们干这一票
I hired Matsui, and Matsui hired you.
他就是向班奈狄泄密的家伙
That's the guy who dimed us to Benedict.
-他们全部?包括欧逊?  -对
- All of them, including Ocean. - Yes.
一个
月
之前
我不信  你是谁?
I find that hard to believe. And you are?
你可以叫我夜狐
You can call me the Night Fox.
夜狐?夜狐先生
The Night Fox. Okay, Mr. Night Fox.
-这消息要多少钱?   -放心  不用钱
- What will this information cost me? - Don't worry. Nothing.
不用钱?少唬我  没有什么是不用钱的
Nothing? Who do you think you're dealing with? Nothing costs nothing.
这消息的价值很难用钱衡量
And this information is definitely worth something.
姑且说咱们目前的兴趣相同
Let's just say our interests are temporarily aligned.
怎么说?
How so?
我不要钱  不过我有一些条件
Well, the information is free, but it comes with certain conditions.
-什么条件?   -你必须有点节制
- Such as? - Restraint on your part.
节制?这要求很高  还有呢?
Restraint? That's asking a lot. What else?
给他们两个礼拜时间去凑钱
Two weeks to buy themselves out of trouble.
两个礼拜
Two weeks?
我能接受  虽然他们不见得能
I can live with that, even if they can't.
我很好奇  你要多少钱?
Just out of curiosity, what will you make them pay?
饶他们一命?他们偷走的钱加上利息
For letting them live? Everything they stole, plus interest.
很高的利息
A lot of interest.
那笔钱保险公司都赔给你了
But didn't your insurance cover what was stolen?
没错
Of course.
你要他们加倍偿还这笔钱
So you're asking them to double your money?
你不觉得不公平吗?
Well, do you really think that's fair?
不公平?越不公平越好  你说的消息呢?
Fair? I certainly hope not. So, what about the information?
就在你办公桌上
Okay. It's on your desk.
他半夜三点半来过这儿
He was here. Around 3:30 this morning. I can tell.
-谁?  -夜狐
- Who? - The Night Fox.
到丹客提咖啡馆抓松井
Go down to the Dampkring and pick up a guy called Matsui.
真名是伊恩尼可拉麦纳利
Real name, Ian Nicolas McNally.
夜狐跟美国人同时下手?为什么?
The Night Fox was here at the same time as the Americans? Why?
所以我们要查出真相呀
That's what we're gonna find out.
他在干嘛?
What is he doing?
把他叫出来
Get him out of there.
天啊
God.
那家伙守口如瓶
要他开口比登天还难
指甲美容院
你好  法兰克
Hello, Frank.
咱们到底是哪里惹到这家伙?
I can't understand what we did to this guy.
-他干嘛对我们不爽?  -他又怎么弄到密码的?
- Why does he have it out for us like this? - How did he get that code?
这不重要  他犯了行规  被列入黑名翠
Doesn't matter. He broke rule number one. He's on the list.
这节骨眼还要争地盘
Great time for a turf war.
我跟法兰克的朋友通过电话  她会查出这家伙名宇
I spoke with Frank's associate in Dublin. She's trying to get us a name on this guy.
火车明天一点半出发
Our train leaves tomorrow at 1:38, okay?
-法兰克人呢?   -我不知道
- Where is Frank? - I don't know.
这件丑事一定会传出去  到时候我们会没案子接
It's gonna get out. Then we'll be dead, and no one will wanna work with us.
清理客房
Housekeeping.
我要为莱恩先生整理房问
Turndown service for Mr. Ryan.
嗨
Hi.
很棒的套房
Nice room.
你一个人住吗?
You have it all to yourself?
你要抓我吗?
You here to take me in?
我为什么要抓你?你又没有偷东西
Why would I do that? It's not as if you stole something.
罗伯  很高兴能再见到你
It's nice to see you again, Robert.
我也是
You too.
当然罗  你经常来看我
Of course, you've been seeing plenty of me, haven't you?
我喜欢这张
I like this one.
我取名为"小偷加冰淇淋"
I call it "thief ?la mode. "
你用了舒曼那一招
Schumann Special, huh?
谁叫我当时那么大嘴巴告诉你
I guess that's what I get for opening my mouth.
夜狐怎么样?
So, what about the Night Fox?
他有没有留言给你?
Did he leave you a message?
小玩偶还在吗?
What about the figurine? You still have it?
我猜这算是一种赞美
I suppose it's a compliment in a way.
他觉得你是个对手  我倒不这么认为
I guess he's threatened by you, though I can't imagine why.
你不知道他有多厉害
You have no idea what you're up against.
法国警方认为  他比勒马克强
The French police think he's better than LeMarc.
他是法国人
Well, he is French.
我给你个良心建议
Let me give you some advice.
查出你怎么惹毛了他  向他道歉求饶
Find out how you offended him. Apologize. Beg for mercy.
我得走了
Got to go.
想传话给法兰克吗?他在警局里
Any message for Frank? He's been hanging around the station.
什么罪名?
On what charge?
犯罪现场找到一双战斗靴的印子
Well, we found a print of a size 14 Hi-Tec Magnum boot at the crime scene.
所以呢?
And?
用盗刷信用卡买的
Bought with a fraudulent credit card.
而且阿姆斯特丹只有一两家高级指甲美容院
From that point on, well, there's only one, maybe two great nail salons in Amsterdam.
-你骗了我们  -也骗了我
- And you lied to us. - Yeah, and to me.
法兰克早就知道了
Well, Frank knew.
-他知道你跟她联络?  -我没跟她联络
- Frank knew you were in touch? - I wasn't in touch.
只是跟踪她
I was more like keeping tabs.
-她是个警察 　-其实是警探
- She's a cop! - Detective, actually.
-舒曼那一招她哪学来的?  -老爸教的
- Where'd she learn all that Schumann crap? - Dad.
-他也是警察?  -他是小偷
- What, he was a cop? - Thief.
-他很厉害吗?   -很厉害
- Oh, God. Was he good? - Oh, yeah.
抓狂前女友的神偷老爸
Great. Pissed-off ex-girlfriend whose thief father...
把一身本领传授给她
...taught her every trick in the book.
她认得出丹尼跟小颜了
Well, she just made Danny and Yen.
过两天欧洲每一间警局就会有你们的照片
In the next 48 hours, your pictures will be in every police station.
-没人会看 　-警察就会看
- Nobody looks at them. - Nobody but cops.
-是警探 　-她老爸是同行
- Detectives. - You'd think she'd have sympathy for us...
-也许会同情我们 　-同情还是怜悯?
...if her old man was a thief. - Is that sympathy or empathy?
她九岁那年老爸就被逮捕  后来死在牢里
No, her old man got popped a day before her 9th birthday. Died in jail.
她不会同情或怜悯我们
So I wouldn't count on much sympathy. Or empathy.
饭店一定受到监视
She's gonna have the hotel under surveillance.
这下只能叫客房服务  看电视  直到班奈狄干掉我们
Great. We'll just eat room service, watch movies and wait for Benedict to kill us.
-百元大钞上面是谁?  -亚当斯
- Who's on the $ 100 bill? - Adams.
-约翰屈伏塔 　-他说过危机...
- John Travolta. - He said every problem...
就是转机
...is an opportunity in disguise.
他死到临头就不会这么说了
He couldn't say that with a. 45 in his mouth.
你们要往好处想
No, you're missing the silver lining here.
她给了个名字"夜狐"
Now, she gave us a name, didn't she? The Night Fox.
通电话就能查出他的底细
One phone call, we're gonna find out everything there is to know about this guy.
第二个星期四
只剩六天
我姓狄亚兹  米嘉狄亚兹
The name is M. Diaz. D-I-A-Z.
黑色旅行袋
It's a black duffel bag.
球队在鹿特丹  行李在布鲁塞尔
The team's in Rotterdam. The bag's in Brussels.
一个现代人和社会完全断线
He's the modern man: Disconnected, frightened...
惊慌失措  六神无主
...paranoid, but with good reason.
太惨了  不好笑
It's too sad to be funny. Unusable.
-我可以编成一段二十分钟的脱口秀 　-太好了
- I think I can get 20 minutes out of it. - Great.
球队在巴塞隆纳  行李在马德里
I got it. The team's in Barcelona. The bag's in Madrid.
太夸张了  这是不道德的
This is a moral issue we're dealing with here.
而且又失去一位好手  因为他被困在一个袋子里
And we don't have a grease man anymore, because he's in a bag somewhere.
可以叫他袋子男
We got a bag man.
你真是个没心肝的禽兽
Such an ape. An animal with no feelings.
-我有啊 　-才没有
- I have feelings. - No, you don't.
他困在行李袋里面  我也为他难过
I feel bad for the guy. He's in a piece of luggage, but he's got water.
-况且他们能怎么办呢?  -下车去找他呀
- What did you want them to do? - Get off the bus.
他们太显眼了啦
And pick up the bag with our friend in it.
哪支足球队会有五十岁老先生?
How many pro soccer teams are fielding 50-year-old men?
罗斯并没有五十岁
Rusty's not 50 years old.
是啊  我们知道
Yeah, dude, we know Rusty's not 50.
你觉得我有五十岁?我问你
You think I'm 50 years old? Let me ask you something.
不  我问你
No, wait, let me ask you something.
我看起来几岁?
How old do you think I am?
48岁
Forty-eight.
你觉得我有48岁?
You think I'm 48 years old?
52岁吗?
Fifty-two?
-他应该问我才对 　-谁都别来问你
- Maybe he should've asked me. - Nobody should ever ask you anything.
他已经够难过了  你还这样
That guy doesn't have a hard enough life right now? You gotta...
你在替他说话?他把小颜塞进手提袋耶
You're gonna defend him? They put Yen in a handbag.
-我问你... 你有没有注意到 　-想问什么就直说
- Can I ask you something? Ever notice...? - Lf you're gonna ask a question...
除非这句话是口头禅
...give me time to respond, unless it's rhetorical...
我就会说好
...in which case the answer is obvious: Yes.
-好  我问你 　-好
- Okay, can I ask...? - Yes.
-你不觉得泰丝长得很像...   -别问到这事
- You ever notice that Tess looks exactly...? - Don't ever ask that. Seriously.
-别跟任何人问起这事  尤其是她 　-为什么?
- Not to anyone. Especially not to her. - Wait. Why not?
听好
Look.
我这人不爱耍神秘
It's not in my nature to be mysterious...
但只有这件事  我得守口如瓶
...but I can't talk about it, and I can't talk about why.
-我看起来有五十岁吗?  -有啊
- Can I ask you...? Do I look 50 to you? - Yeah.
-真的假的?   -其实咧... 只有脖子以上啦
- Really? - Well, I mean, only from the neck up.
索尔?
Saul?
你怎么了?
What's the matter?
没事
Nothing.
你想出门吗?天气不错喔
You wanna go out? It's nice.
不想
No.
你想看球赛吗?
You wanna watch something? The game's on.
不想
No.
-饿了吗?我去热菜 　-不要
- You hungry? I'll heat something up. - No.
索尔  自从你回来以后就怪怪的
Saul, ever since you got back, you've been acting strange.
丹尼要你做什么?
What did Danny want?
没什么
Nothing.
没什么?那怎么可能?
Nothing? How could he want nothing?
夜狐的真名是法兰斯瓦杜鲁
All right, the Night Fox has a name. Francis Toulour.
法兰斯瓦杜鲁男爵
Baron Francis Toulour.
父亲是富翁  母亲是贵族
Father was a French industrialist, mother was Italian nobility.
他从没见过他妈  但他继承了她的爵位
He never met her, but he inherited her title.
他多金  无聊  又高明
The bad news is he's rich, he's bored and he's talented.
他是神偷勒马克的徒弟
The really bad news is he was trained by LeMarc.
-情况不妙 　-盖斯伯勒马克?
- This is not good. - With the LeMarc? Gaspar LeMarc?
没错
That's the one.
-我们完蛋了 　-我们还没完蛋
- Well, we're doomed. - We're not doomed.
-他只有一个人  又是法国佬 　-对
- He's one guy, and he's French. - Yeah.
先别被他的显赫身世吓到
Before we get too impressed by his background...
他干过什么大案?
- ... let's hear what he's done.
他九十年代初入行  干过...
- He started in the '90s.
日门瓦银行  丹麦国库  意大利银行  荷兰银行
Bank of Geneva, the Danish Treasury, the Bank of Italy, AMC Amro...
布鲁塞尔钻石交易中心  安特卫普钻石交易中心
...the Brussels Diamond Exchange, Antwerp Diamond Exchange.
-全是在九十年代干的?  -这只是到96年而已
- Wait, wait. All those in the 1990s? - I'm only up to '96.
-真的假的?  -97年他改偷艺术品
- Seriously? - In '97, he went through an art phase.
伦敦泰德画廊  罗浮宫  两次
He hit the Tate in London, the Louvre in Paris, twice, and the Prado.
还有普拉多美术馆  普拉多那一票是莫瑞提干的
Wait. No, no, hang on. The Prado Museum in '97? That was Moretti.
-大家都知道...   -莫瑞提是他的假名之一
- Everybody knows that... - He is Moretti. It's one of his aliases.
我跳到最精彩的一票
Okay, I'll skip to my favorite.
2002年他偷走摩洛哥国王的游艇  凭空消失了
In 2002, he stole the king of Morocco's 200-foot yacht. Vanished into thin air.
船员几天后获救  什么都不记得
Crew surfaced days later in a life raft. Couldn't remember a thing.
-一艘游艇要藏在哪儿?   -国王就算知道也不肯说
- How do you hide a 200-foot yacht? - If the king knows, he's not telling.
他一个月后拿回游艇  现在每星期都跟杜鲁打网球
He got it back a month later. He now plays tennis with Toulour every weekend.
-这次咱们的麻烦大了 　-没错
- We're in some serious trouble here. - Copy that.
-我们怎么办?   -反应
- So, what do we do? - We respond.
-怎么反应?   -以牙还牙
- Respond? How? - In kind.
意大利  科木湖
第二个星期五
只剩五天
欧逊先生
Mr. Ocean.
你违反了行规  就得付出代价
You broke rule number one, and that has consequences.
你是指那几幅画吗?
Oh, you must be talking about the paintings.
别担心  五天后你死了... 我就能拿回来
Don't worry. You'll be dead in five days, and I'll get my paintings back.
-除非你先出意外 　-我想不会吧  丹尼
- Unless you have an accident first. - I don't think so, Daniel.
让我解释  我为何要折磨你
Perhaps I should explain to you why I'm tormenting you.
请说
I'd like that.
上个月我到葡萄牙见我师父
Last month I was in Portugal to see my mentor.
-勒马克 　-没错
- LeMarc. - Indeed.
那天来了一个大嘴巴的美国佬
A very loud and annoying American businessman was there the same day.
他替一家保险公司做事
He worked for a big insurance company.
他就是建议你向班奈狄下手的人
He's the one who suggested Benedict to you as a potential mark.
-你认识他吗?  -他怎么样?
- You know the man? - What about him?
他说那是他见过最高明的窃案
He said it was the most beautiful job he'd ever seen.
他一直说个不停  最后还说
He went on and on about this job, and then he said...
这证明你是世上最伟大的神偷
...it showed you were the greatest thief in the world.
最槽的是  勒马克并没有反驳
But the worst part is that LeMarc never corrected him.
我说你不可能比我更厉害
I told LeMarc that you can't be better than me.
他却说  这永远无法确定
And he answered that it was impossible to know for sure.
我为了这件事茶不思饭不想  整整想了三个礼拜
So I thought about that for, like, three weeks in a row, day and night.
后来  我突然觉悟了他说得没错
And then suddenly, I realized that he was actually right.
两个小偷没办法同台较劲
It is impossible to compare one theft to the other.
想要一较高下  唯一的办法...
So I guess the only way to know who's the best of us for sure...
就是去偷同一样东西
...is to go after the same object. Do the same job.
你不觉得这样很好玩吗?
Don't you think that would be fun?
你为了玩这无聊游戏枉顾人命
You're being awfully cavalier with a lot of people's lives so you can play out a game.
你一定会后悔的
You're gonna regret it.
别傻了  欧逊先生
Come on, Mr. Ocean.
你弄不到九千七百万美元的
How are you gonna possibly get $97 million by next Wednesday?
我会把每一个保险箱偷光
Especially if every safe you crack between now and then is already empty?
如果你接受挑战  赢了这场比赛
Whereas if you accept my challenge and win...
我就帮你还钱给班奈狄
...I promise I'll pay your debt to Benedict...
勒马克会帮我保管这笔钱
...and LeMarc will hold my money in escrow as a guarantee.
我们要偷什么?
What are we stealing?
巴黎
着名的俄国沙皇加冕彩蛋
The famous Faberg?Coronation Egg.
-这是你还是勒马克的主意?  -他应该会同意...
- Was that your idea or LeMarc's? - I think he would agree...
这是最好的目标
...that it's the most appropriate thing for us to compete over.
它在哪里
Where is it located?
今天一早从巴黎送到罗马
The egg left Paris this morning on its way to Rome.
一路上戒备森严  有一个或更多复制品
It travels with heavy security and usually with one or more replicas.
有时候展览的  也可能是复制品
Sometimes they even show the replicas without anybody knowing.
彩蛋将在星期一一早开始展览
When the egg goes on display Monday morning...
你要在48小时内偷出来
...you'll have 48 hours to steal it before your deadline's up.
期限到了  你没把它偷出来
When the deadline passes and you don't have the egg...
勒马克就知道... 谁才是第一名
...LeMarc will know who's the best.
伊莎贝拉希芮  打击犯罪小组资深警探
-罗斯的手机 　-你是谁?
- Rusty's phone. - Who is this?
妮可  你是谁?
Nicole. Who's this?
奈格  罗斯呢?
Nagel. Where's Rusty?
他说他在甘特那儿
He said if you called, to say he was at Gunther's.
他有说他在那儿干什么吗?
Gunther's? What's that about? Did he say something?
要我传话吗?
Do you have a message?
好  跟他说价钱要加倍
Yes, I do. Tell him this thing is gonna cost him double what I told him.
我得把表面做得更薄
And tell him I had to go three times as thin on the layers.
如果他明天就要  价钱就会更高
And tell him if he wants it tomorrow, it should cost him more than double.
就说这玩意超美的
And tell him this thing is beautiful.
就连沙皇也会被骗倒
Would fool the bloody Romanovs themselves.
跟他说我人很好  还有他打扮得像牛郎
And tell him I'm being a nice guy. And tell him he dresses like a gigolo.
就这样?
Is that it?
等等  跟他说找了个性感女助手
Yeah. No. Tell him having a sexy female assistant...
真的是有够老套了
...is such a terrible clich?
意大利语
可以煮杯咖啡给我吗?
Can I get a coffee or something?
谢了  什么咖啡都行
Thanks. Just a cappuccino or espresso.
好了...
Well...
罗马
第二个星期六
只剩四天
你礼拜六要我到办公室
You call me on Saturday and ask me to come into my office...
要我签1077表格
...and sign a 1077...
却不肯说他们要偷什么?
...and you can't even tell me what they are after?
-我可以到你家 　-我要到那不勒斯度假
- I can come to your house. - I'm leaving for Naples in two hours.
-等到礼拜三再说 　-到时候它就会被偷走了
- We'll talk about this on Wednesday. - It'll be gone by Wednesday.
-什么东西?  -值得你签1077表格的东西
- What? What? What will be gone? - Something worth signing a 1077 for.
莱恩一伙人干下赌场那一票
Ryan and his friends did the Bellagio casino heist in 2001.
-这是件大案子 　-如果是这样...
- I am telling you, this is serious... - If that's true...
-那就该找美国联邦调查局 　-不行
- ... then we should call the American FBl... - No, no, no.
-听我说 　-拉希芮警探
- Maurizio, listen to me. - Agent Lahiri...
1077表格不能随便乱签
...a 1077 is not a small thing.
你不跟我说他们要偷什么  就没什么好谈的
Unless you can tell me what they are after, there is no point in discussing it.
俄国沙皇加冕彩蛋
嘿...
Hey...
勒马克在1980年打败了23个小偷  把它偷走了
Because LeMarc stole it in 1980 when 23 others failed.
现在夜狐要证明  他比莱恩以及他的朋友们强
Because the Night Fox is trying to prove he's better than Ryan and his friends.
胡扯一通  你先说他们要偷彩蛋
This is ridiculous. You say the egg will be stolen.
又说勒马克24年前就把它偷走了
Then you say LeMarc already stole it 24 years ago.
-哪种说法是真的?  -都是
- Which one is it? - Both.
什么?
What?
勒马克的老婆逼他归还彩蛋
LeMarc's wife made him put the egg back.
宝格丽案我签了1077表格
When I signed a 1077 for you on the Bulgari case...
你用了我30个手下3个月  连一个嫌犯都没逮到
...you requisitioned 30 of my men for three months and made zero arrests.
我不会再帮你
I won't do it again.
晚上不行
First, we cannot go at night.
不可能穿过雷射防盗网
The laser grid in the Great Hall's impossible to beat.
-没有不可能的事 　-这就是不可能的事
- Nothing's impossible. - This is impossible.
雷射光线不断随机移动
It's in constant motion, programmed to improvise randomly...
根本无法控制
...meaning we can't plan our way through.
好吧
All right.
那就要在白天下手
So it's a daytime play.
伊莎贝认得你  小颜跟丹尼  所以还缺三个人
We're still short three on the inside since Isabel made you and Yen and Danny.
可以用走私乐园那一招
We could try a Smuggler's Paradise.
-1950年之后就没用过 　-其实是54年
- It hasn't worked since the '50s. - '54, actually.
还有什么招术?
What's option two?
宝贝珍  车轮战  再用二儿子
Baby Jane, Squeaky Wheel, followed by a Number-Two Son.
有点复杂  不过成功率很高  唯一的问题是...
It's complicated, but it's got a high success rate. The only problem is...
小颜不上场  就办不到
We can't do it without a grease man on the inside, without Yen.
只好冒险让他乔装上阵了
We'll have to risk it. We'll put him in disguise.
第二个星期日
只剩三天
10点10分  我走出咖啡馆 　10点11分?
10:10, I leave the caf? proceed west. 10:11?
-我躲进二楼厕所 　-10点13分
- I enter the second-floor bathroom. - 10:13?
我从南边走上西班牙台阶
Approach the Spanish Steps from the south.
我跟拜许一起进去
Basher and I enter by the main entrance.
-10点15分 　-我帮小颜进入通风孔
- 10:15? - I help Yen into the ventilation duct.
-10点18分 　-我跟鲁本进展览厅
- 10:18? - I move Reuben to the Egg Room.
-我在大厅逗留 　-我也进展览厅
- I pause in the Great Hall while... - I go to the Egg Room.
-10点21分 　-小颜潜入电脑主机室
- 10:21? - Yen enters the mainframe room.
切断电源  然后通知我  我给莱纳斯打信号
He cuts power to grid 14-A. He radios me. I signal Linus.
-然后我就走进展览厅 　-10点22分
- I then go to the Egg Room. - 10:22?
我把鲁本带到他的位置
I drop my keys and move Reuben to his mark.
-我挡住一号摄影机 　-我挡住二号摄影机
- I blind camera one. - I blind camera two.
-我挡住三号摄影机 　-我挡住四号摄影机
- I blind camera three. - Camera four.
-我负责偷天换日 　-很好
- I make the switch. - Right.
-10点24分 　-我开车到入口西南角
- 10:24? - I pull to the corner of the main entrance.
我跟丹尼会合往北走 　10点25分
I meet Danny at the Steps. We head north. 10:25?
我跟塔克负责送货
Turk and I make the drop.
很好  非常好
All right. Really good stuff, guys.
非常好  一小时后出发
Really good work. All right, we'll pick it up here in an hour.
一定成功
It's a slam-dunk.
-很好 　-10点45分我们被逮捕
- Great. - 10:45, we all get arrested.
没错
You bet.
-杜鲁怎样?   -老样子
- How was Toulour? - He was predictable.
奈格有消息吗?
You hear from Nagel?
他会来
He'll be here.
奈格那种人不太可靠
That's a lot to presume from a guy like Nagel.
你要催他
Follow it up.
我是伊莎贝
This is Isabel.
这是约翰  你六点要跟安卓西蒙碰面
It's Johan. I just set a 6:00 meeting for you with an Andre Ciment...
他在科木湖的豪宅丢了四幅名画
...who says he had four paintings stolen from his house in Lake Como.
-什么时候?  -礼拜五
- And when was this? - Sometime Friday.
莫内两幅  透纳和窦加各一幅
He's missing two Monets, a Turner and a Degas.
-窦加的哪一幅?  -《蓝色舞群》
- Which Degas was it? - Blue Dancers.
他说监视摄影机有录到窃贼  不过还没有确认
Supposedly, there's surveillance video, but I haven't been able to confirm that yet.
关键是更正错误
It is all about error correction.
一共有三千条透明数位细线
Three thousand separate, translucent, digital slivers...
不是我原来说的一千条
...instead of the 1000 I thought it would be.
幸好不必移动这玩意
Thank God it doesn't have to move.
重造光源非常麻烦  我融合了钨丝灯泡和自然光
Re-creating the lighting was a pain. It's a mixture of tungsten and real light.
不过  色彩校正很精准
But I think the color rendition is pretty damn accurate.
电池藏在基座  最多两分钟
Batteries are in the base. Two minutes maximum.
你很厉害
You're good.
真的很棒  你是个天才 　我的确是
- It's good, Roman. You're a genius. - I think I am.
你们没有我  根本就进不去
You'd have never got past that grid.
所以价钱要加倍
That's why you're paying me double.
-什么?不行 　-我给你留了言
- What? No, no, no. - You got my message.
-那个性感声音很像庞德女郎 　-什么留言?
- Who's that sexy phone voice? Early Bond. - What message?
我给性感美女的留言呀
The message I left with Sexy Phone Voice Nicole.
替你接手机的妮可
On your mobile.
甘特那一票有我的份吗?
Got something going with Gunther? Am I in?
-你几时留的言?  -两天前
- Okay, when did you leave the message? - Two days ago.
她替你接手机
She had your phone.
-她拿了你的...   -对
- She has your...? - Yeah.
-这代表她...   -没错
- That means that she's...? - Yeah.
-那你最好...  -是啊
- Well, you better... - Yeah.
-这下可好了 　-我意思是...
- That's great. - I mean...
我的钱呢?
So...? So who's got my money?
谁来付我钱?
Who has got my bloody money?
天啊
Jesus.
我听说你妈过世了  我很遗憾
Sorry to hear about your mom.
她很了不起
She was an amazing...
至少我是这么想
Well, I thought so, at least.
她讨厌你  我早该想到了
She hated you. I should've picked up on that.
-她最讨厌小偷 　-怪不得你们常吵架
- She hated all thieves. - No wonder you fought.
什么?
Excuse me?
-手机还我 　-不要
- May I have my phone back? - No.
-手法很高明 　-谢了
- That's a nice pull, by the way. - Thanks.
你下手时有没有很爽?
Did you get that tingling sensation down your spine when you did it?
也许我不该过问
Or is that none of my business?
你想改行吗?
You considered a career change?
你想吗?
Have you?
我开过饭店
I tried hotels.
但我干这行比较行
I'm better at this.
我去吃了提拉米苏
Went by the caf?for some tiramisu.
-跟以前不一样了 　-夜狐是谁?
- It wasn't the same. - Who's the Night Fox?
-师傅用的蛋不一样 　-你为什么接受这个挑战?
- They did something to the eggs. - Why accept his challenge?
因为他会输
Because he'll lose.
你们能赢他?
And how can you beat him?
不能
We can't.
那我就不懂了
You're not making any sense.
好吧
Okay.
你跟法兰克犯下了宝格丽窃案
The Bulgari job you pulled with Frank when we were together...
我早就猜到是你
...I knew it was you.
你为什么不说?
Why didn't you say something?
Why didn't you...
罗伯?
...Robert?
我不想要结束我们之间的事
I didn't want it to end.
那是你自己猜会结束的
You assumed it would.
我猜错了吗?
Was I wrong?
你不该来的
You shouldn't be here.
我得去开会了
I have a meeting.
有人在科木湖偷了名画
Someone stole a whole bunch of paintings in Lake Como.
是吗?有线索吗?
Interesting. Any leads?
下次我见到你...
The next time I see you...
肯定把你跟欧逊...
...I'm arresting you.
和我认得的人全都抓起来
And Ocean and anybody else I recognize.
好吧
Fair enough.
-好了吗?  -好了
- Ready? - Right.
法语
对不起  你会讲英文吗?
当然会
Yes, of course I do.
窦加的《蓝色舞群》
My Blue Dancers, my Degas.
他们偷走了  我很想...
They took it, unfortunately, and I really would like...
你有仇家吗?
Do you have any enemies?
你有得罪过什么人吗?
Anybody out there who would feel wronged by you?
没有啊  我想不出来
No. I can't see anyone.
你认为那个贼...
But why? You think... You think maybe the thief...
是冲着我来?
...is trying to harm me personally now?
我以为他是为了那些画
Well, I assumed he was after the paintings themselves.
那些画很值钱
I think it's enough.
好了吗?
Ready?
行吗?
Good?
我有样东西  你可能会有兴趣
I have something you might be interested in.
我房子的监视摄影机DVD
It's a DVD with all the hidden surveillance cameras I have to my place.
我有很多  我还没看过
It's plenty. I haven't checked it out yet.
也许小偷会不小心被拍到
Maybe the thieves have been careless enough to be photographed.
他们很高明  应该不会  不过我会看看
I doubt it, this level of thief, but I'll take a look.
搞不好有拍到
Yeah. You never know.
谢谢
Okay. Well, merci.
谢谢你  谢谢你的帮忙
Thank you, Mademoiselle Lahiri, for everything.
再见
Thank you. Goodbye. Goodbye.
拉希芮小姐
Mademoiselle Lahiri.
你收到1077表格传真了吗?
Did you get the faxed copy of the 1077? Good.
很好  听好  我要调动十二名制服员警
Here's what I need: A dozen... Twelve uniformed officers.
金属探测器  额外摄影机
Metal detectors, extra cameras.
我会把照片传给你  有笔吗?
So I'll e-mail you the photographs. Do you happen to have a pen?
我告诉你姓名
I'll just give you the names. Okay.
李文斯顿载尔  白人男子  168公分  68公斤
Livingston Dell, male, Caucasian, 5'6", 150 pounds.
维吉马洛伊  白人男子  178公分  73公斤
Virgil Malloy, male, Caucasian, 5' 10", 160 pounds.
罗伯莱恩  白人男子
Robert Ryan, male, Caucasian...
-喂?  -早安
- Hello? - Buon giorno, Mr. Eisenhower.
这是五点钟晨唤服务
This is your 5 a. m. Wake-up call.
-五点了?  -是的
- Really? - Yes, I'm afraid.
祝您愉快
Have a nice day, sir.
-嗨 　-你在干嘛?
- Hey. - What are you doing?
睡觉啊  你穿好衣服干嘛?
- What...? Sleeping. Why are you dressed?
五点半了  该出发了
- It's 5:30, day of. We gotta go. Let's go.
现在才十一点半
It's 11:30.
前一天的晚上
The night before.
但是...
But...
他好贱哦  他好坏哦
Oh, he's mean. He's just mean-spirited.
-你喝了几杯浓缩咖啡?   -五杯
- How many espressos did you have? - Five.
进来吧
Yeah, come on.
我不知道她是闹脾气...
I don't know if she's just confused...
还是真的把我恨之入骨
...or she's really turned the corner and hates me now.
我做得到底对不对?
You think I handled this wrong?
我太霸道  太像美国佬了
I was too forceful. I was too American.
她跟我们不同
She's different.
你说得对  也许她不爱我了
Maybe you're right, maybe she has moved on.
我想过要把刺青除掉
You know, I talked to a doctor about getting that tattoo removed.
不过因为位置尴尬  医生说最好不要
But given its location, he advised against it.
意大利配音员真不是盖的
That guy doing Potsie is unbelievable.
第二个星期一
只剩两天
这家伙有什么毛病?
I mean, what's this guy's problem?
他为了面子  整了我们两次
He's stitched us up twice in two weeks, all over his ego.
咱们难得能好好共度一晚
It's the first decent evening we've had together in I don't know how long.
够了  咱们谈正事吧
All right, all right, let's just stay on point here.
再过滤一下清单
Let's go over the list again.
谁死了让你当老大?
Who died and made you Danny?
没有啊
No one.
抱歉  我只是心情很乱
I'm sorry. My emotions are all over the place.
是我不应该
I was forceful, trying to show good leadership...
-废话少说  谈正事吧 　-你是个好领袖
- For fuck's sake. Let's go. - You're a good leader.
谢了
Thanks.
好吧  再过滤一下清单
All right, well, let's go over the list again.
-假扮神父那招? -人手不够
- Swinging Priest? - Not enough people.
-疯子赖瑞?   -人手不够
- Crazy Larry? - Not enough people.
-肩头酸痛?   -人手不够
- Soft Shoulder? - Not enough people.
-面包师傅? 找不到女生  -人手也不够
- Baker's Dozen? - No woman and not enough people.
菜篮族地狱?
Hell in a Hand basket?
没时间训练猫咪  人手还是不够
We can't train a cat that quickly. And not enough people.
-泰丝呢?   -她怎么样?
- What about Tess? - What about her?
她长得有点像
Well, you know how she kind of looks like...
-又怎样?  -是啊  你想说什么?
- So what? - Yeah, what's your point?
用声东击西那一招
So we do a Lookie-loo.
-声东击西加上混水摸鱼 　-找泰丝...
- It's a Lookie-loo with a Bundle of Joy. - A Lookie-loo with Tess...
用这两招?
...and a Bundle of Joy?
你发疯了  小子
You've gone right out of your tree, my son. He's mad.
他疯了  简直异想天开  而且还缺一个人
It's crazy. It's Italian-television crazy, and we're still one short.
想想看  她能在白天接近彩蛋
No, think about it. She can get near the egg during daylight with half the system down.
保安系统至少能解除一半
这是一石三鸟之计
I mean, that's a trifecta.
他说得有道理  打电话
He might be right. Make the calls.
莱纳斯卡得威  你这臭小子
Linus Caldwell, you are not following the procedures...
你没按照我跟丹尼说好的程序
...Danny talked about if Terry Benedict shows up.
一定出了事  出了什么事?
Something is wrong. What is wrong?
丹尼没事  他跟罗斯在一起
Danny's fine. He's with Rusty.
只是现在他们处于失去联络状态
During this part of the plan, they can't communicate with us.
向我保证他没受伤
Promise he isn't hurt.
我保证他没受伤
I promise he isn't hurt.
你们会错过期限
You're gonna miss the deadline.
我想这一票干完  丹尼一定很想在罗马见到你
Danny would be thrilled if you met him in Rome when the job's finished.
他想你想得要命
He misses you like crazy.
你念过艺术  一定很爱罗马
Plus, you studied art, so I know how much you love Rome.
只有好处  没有坏处
There's no downside here.
他们把你调教得真好
Wow, they're bringing you along fast, aren't they?
是啊  如果你搭上七点的...
Yes. Danny would be more thrilled...
... 班机就太棒了  你现在就得出门
...if you were on the 7 p. m. Out of JFK, which means you have to leave right now.
第二个星期二
只剩一天
我只要求一台中型房车
I thought I'd requested a midsize.
-丹尼有来吗?  -他很想来
- Danny here? - He wanted to be.
这趟飞行舒适吗?我不确定你要走道或窗口座位
Did you have a nice flight? We weren't sure if you were a window or aisle person.
-丹尼被关了多久?   -只有两天  真的
- How long's Danny been in jail? - Just a couple of days, really.
往好处想  班奈狄动不了他
Which, you know, on the bright side, he's completely safe from Benedict.
他说一切OK  居然敢骗我
He told me everything was fine. He lied right to me.
我想他的意思是  我们的时间和金钱都不多
What I think he meant by "fine" is we're running low on time and money...
现在欠的钱  比一开始更多
...and we're deeper in debt than when we started.
我想你们有计划要救他吧
I assume that you have a plan to get him out.
-她说起话来很像她 　-才怪  她有南方口音
- Actually, she sounds like her. - No, she needs a Southern accent.
-你会装南方腔吗?   -你们在搞什么鬼?
- Can you do a Southern...? - What the hell is going on with you guys?
这样不行  口音很重要  人们最注意口音
Not quite. The accent is crucial. It's the first thing people notice.
-给我说清楚  开辆顶级礼车干嘛?   -抱歉
- This ridiculous car, what is it doing? - Okay, I'm sorry.
我就直话直说吧  因为我们不幸...
All right, I'm just gonna level with you. Due to certain personnel losses...
折损了一些人手
...that we have sustained...
我们得做一些调整
...we're... Various readjustments had to be made.
你要扮演一个小角色
You're gonna have to play a small role in this thing.
请你把这个戴上
Okay? So can you put these on?
还有这顶帽子
I'd like you to put this hat on.
穿上孕妇装  底下塞枕头
You're gonna put on that, and you're gonna stuff it with that.
我们转过去  给你点隐私
And we'll turn around, just give you a little moment.
小角色
Small role.
我要扮谁?
Who am I supposed to be?
这个嘛...
Well...
真的吗?
Oh, really?
没问题
Well, absolutely.
我们可以把套房空出来
I can have... We can make the suite available.
不会麻烦
No, no, no trouble at all.
这真是太... 她再度莅临  我们深感荣幸
I mean, we would love... We are honored that she would think of us again.
好的
Okay.
谢谢
Okay. Thank you.
再见
Bye.
茱莉亚罗勃兹要来
这要怎么把丹尼救出来?
How is this going to get Danny out?
-我们需要一个名人 　-怎么不去找一个?
- We needed someone famous. - Why didn't you get someone famous?
回想《你是我今生的新娘》
Just think Four Weddings and a Funeral.
那部电影不是她演的
She wasn't in Four Weddings and a Funeral.
要说"我"  不是"我"演的
"I." "I wasn't in Four Weddings and a Funeral. "
保护你的假胎儿
Just protect your fake baby.
天啊  我快昏倒了
I'm hyperventilating.
-欢迎  罗勃兹小姐 　-谢谢  她很累了
- Welcome back, Signora Roberts. - Thank you. She's very tired.
-拿吧  拿吧  -好
- Take it. Take it. - Okay.
快躲起来
Oh, let's hide. Let's hide.
茱莉亚?
Julia?
我叫泰莉莎
My name is Teresa.
意大利语
我好像见到一位好朋友
I thought I saw a friend of mine, someone that I know.
不  不能关掉压力感测器  不
No, absolutely not. You can't turn off the pressure sensors. No.
她不能碰
Well, she can't touch it.
她只是电影明星  不是教宗
She's a movie star. She's not the pope, for Chris sake.
你是乔治亚州人  67年出生
You're from Smyrna, Georgia. You were born in 1967.
-你喜欢织毛衣 　-中间名是费欧娜
- You like croquet and knitting. - Your middle name is Fiona.
你有十只狗和七匹马
You've got 10 dogs, seven horses.
-你最喜欢桃子的颜色 　-她的马没有比狗多啦
- Your favorite color is peach. - She doesn't have more horses than dogs.
-我不行  我办不到 　-泰丝  没时间了
- I can't do this. I can't. - Tess, we're out of time.
-叫她茱莉亚 　-茱莉亚
- "Julia," please. - Julia.
我知道你很没安全感  这就对了
No, we understand you're feeling insecure. That is totally natural.
-电影明星都很没安全感 　-不是啦  我快抓狂了
- You're playing an actress. They're insecure. - No, I'm not insecure. I'm freaking out.
-这就对了 　-你演得很棒
- Yes. That's right. - Brilliant!
你在演戏
You're playing a role.
你才在演戏  我在冒充一个人
No, you're playing a role. I'm apparently playing a real person.
-又怎样?   -这是不对的
- Yeah, so? - It's just wrong.
你是说很没道德吗?
You mean, like, morally?
不是啦  对... 是啦
No. Well, yes.
这不是重点  你要我冒充一个...
Probably... It's not the point. The point is you want me to speak...
活生生的真人  这太过分了
...for someone who's out there somewhere. It's too personal.
你要害你老公坐一辈子牢吗?
More personal than your husband doing 25-to-life?
他不会坐太久的牢  班奈狄会马上把他做掉
He won't do 25-to-life. Benedict will have him killed immediately.
-不要 　-抱歉  我不该这么说
- Don't. - I'm sorry, that was stupid.
从进去到出来只要花十分钟  我们也只有十分钟
We're gonna be in and out in 10 minutes. We have to. That's our time frame.
你不想说话就别开口  只要微笑对着镜头挥手就行
You don't even have to talk. Give them a big smile, wave at the cameras.
-她只会这一招 　-要是开口...
- That's all she ever does. - But if you do say something...
别忘了南方口音  去掉尾音  母音轻声带过
...don't forget your accent. Drop your G's, and longer vowels.
客房服务
Room service.
不会有事的  你只要记住
It's gonna be fine. You've gotta remember something.
你只是个明星  影迷的偶像
You are an image to these people. You're like an object.
没人真的认识你  你不会碰到任何朋友
Nobody actually knows you. The last thing this is gonna be is personal.
-你的预产期不是过了吗?   -你跑来罗马干嘛?
- Aren't you overdue? - Why are you in Rome?
-我来度假 　-我好爱你
- I'm here on vacation. - I love you.
你怀孕八个月了  不该坐飞机了
You are not supposed to fly eight months pregnant.
-我知道 　-丹尼在吗?
- I know. - Is Danny here?
-当然在 　-丹尼
- Of course. - Danny.
-不是啦 　-他在工作?
- No, no, I mean, he has... - He's working?
-算是啦 　-在罗马?
- Yes. Yes and no. He's working. - In Rome?
-我是葛伦史奈威  宣传公关 　-嗨  葛伦
- Bruce. Glen Snackwell, publicity. - Hey, Glen.
-我是你的超级大影迷 　-谢谢
- I'm a big fan. - Thanks.
你把玛西开除了?
Great. You fired Marcy?
你把她开除  两星期前你才跟我说我应该请她
You fired Marcy. Two weeks ago, you told me I should go with Marcy.
-对不起 　-跟他说玛西的事
- I'm sorry. - Tell him what happened with Marcy, Glen.
-有八卦吗?  - 对  她一向都很八卦
- There's a story? - Always a story with Marcy.
-玛西  玛西...  -你看起来好极了
- Marcy... Marcy... - You look fantastic.
-这真是个惊喜 　-你最好坐下来
- Such a surprise. - You should sit down.
我是电影宣传  玛西没被开除
I'm with the studio. Marcy's still very much in the picture.
我想跟你谈谈
I just wanted to get you for a second.
我们想用生小孩... 替她争取片约
We're looking to come off this baby thing strong.
奥斯卡小金人魔咒... 开始发威了
You know, that little statue on the mantle starts smirking at you after a while.
你懂我的意思吗?
You know what I'm saying?
-我不懂 　-好  抱歉
- Not really, Glen, no. - Sorry. Yeah.
茱莉  我想起来了
Hey, Jules, that reminds me.
我去你家玩之后  一直想打电话给你
I've been meaning to call you since the girls and I were in Taos.
-见到你真好  我好高兴 　-过来  这太脏了
- It's so good to see you. - Come here. These are a mess.
我女儿把她的毯子忘在你家了
Anyway, Tallulah left her SpongeBob blanket in the red casita.
-喔 　-我在想... 来
- Okay. - So, what I wanna do... Here.
-谢谢你 　-不客气
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
-谢谢  布鲁斯 　-打给马可斯...
- Thanks, Bruce. - Is call Marcus...
请他找露易丝  安排人去把毯子拿回来
...and have him get ahold of Louise so we can make arrangements to get it.
他在家吧?
He's home now, right?
-马可斯...   -我也在找马可斯
- Marcus... - I need to talk to Marcus.
-好巧喔  真有趣 　-跟他说一下吧
- That's so funny. What a coincidence. - Go ahead. Talk to him.
到窗口那边... 收讯应该会比较好
Over by the window, with the reception.
-喂?   -马可斯?
- Hello? - Hello, Marcus?
我是茱莉亚  你是哪位?
No, it's Julia. Who's this?
我是茱莉亚  布鲁斯威利也在
It's Julia. I'm with Bruce Willis.
你跟布鲁斯在一起?
You're with Bruce right now?
让我跟他说话  他女儿的卡通毯子
Can I speak with him? Oh, yes, Tallulah's SpongeBob.
-对不起  让我跟他说话 　-断讯了?
- I'm sorry, can I talk to him for a sec? - Did it drop out?
-是啊  断讯了 　-每次都这样
- Yes, it fell out. - That's been happening all week.
-把手机收起来 　-什么?
- Put that phone away right now. - What?
挂断手机  把它收起来
Hang it up and put it away.
你不知道胎儿的大脑...
Do you have any idea how vulnerable...
会受到手机电磁波的损伤吗?
...a fetus' brain is to the electromagnetic field created by your cell phone?
干脆一枪射穿她肚皮算了
You might as well point a gun at her stomach.
-我是布鲁斯威利 　-赛门李波
- I'm Bruce Willis. - Simon Leopold.
-茱莉亚的大夫 　-他是医生
- I am Julia's physician. - He's a doctor.
韦伯医生呢?
What happened to Dr. Webber?
他病了 　韦伯医生在度假
- You know, Doc...? He was sick. - Dr. Webber is on vacation.
-他生病了 　-他度假时病了
- Well, he's sick. - He's sick on vacation.
-度假时病了 　-真扫兴  度假时病了
- Sick on vacation. - Don't you hate that? Sick on vacation.
抱歉吓到你  维大力先生  你很会演戏
Sorry to have jumped on you, Mr. Willis. You do very good actings.
谢谢
Thank you.
-屎蛋 　-史奈威
- Snack bar. - Snackwell.
随便啦  四点钟的活动快开始
It doesn't matter. If we are to get there at 4:00 and do that...
-他们有五成机会 　-不止啦
- I say 50-50. - Closer than that.
我赌二比一他们连进都进不去
- 2- 1 they don't make it to the museum.
五比一他们进不了展览厅
- 5- 1 they don't make it to the Egg Room.
什么?
What?
-她是我老婆 　-你自己也说她很外行
- She's still my wife. - She's a novice. You said so.
-还有一个没出师的学徒 　-被一个高手紧盯不放
- Led by an apprentice. - Being tracked by a pro.
你希望她赢
You want her to win.
-你说谁?   -你知道
- Which her? - You know which her.
-那个始作俑者 　-是啊
- The one that started all this. - Right.
-我以为你说的是...   -才不会  又不是她的错
- Good. For a minute... - Why would I say that? It's not her fault.
-不是她的错 　-没错  好吧
- It wasn't. - Okay, then.
-很好 　-很好
- Good. - Good.
-我被搞混了 　-你们在说谁呀?
- I'm confused. - Yeah, who are you talking about?
-伊莎贝 　-泰丝
- Isabel. - Tess.
-我超爱那部戏  我早猜到了 　-很多人没猜到
- I loved it, but I figured it out. - Not a lot of people did.
-真神奇 　-她在餐厅...
- That's amazing. - The second she doesn't...
一直没跟你说话
...talk to you in the restaurant, I knew...
你就猜出来了?
You figured that out.
-对  不过电影这是很好看 　-太好了
- Yeah, I mean, the movie still works for me. - Great.
她非得走得这么快吗?
Can we just...? Does she really need to be rushing this quickly?
-她简直是在慢跑 　-泰国的...
- She's practically jogging. - In Thailand...
孕妇都在稻田生育  一生完就回去干活
...mothers routinely give birth in rice paddies and then go right back to work.
-母亲真伟大 　-稻田?
- Amazing women over there. - Rice paddy?
她不必这么苦  可以在家里生
She will not have it in a rice paddy. She'll be at her own paddy.
一定会很顺利
And she will be very comfortable because she will be strong...
因为她都有在积极运动
...from this walk and this exercise.
她值得吗?
Was she worth it?
泰丝呢?
Was Tess?
她在餐厅一直没跟你说话  我就知道了
The moment that she doesn't talk to you in the restaurant, I knew.
-没有朋友偷偷告诉你吗?   -没有
- Your friends didn't tell you? - No.
-你自己猜到的?   -对
- That's when you figured it out, huh? - Yeah.
-不过电影还是很好看 　-谢了
- But the movie was still enjoyable for me. - Okay. Thanks.
如果大家都这么聪明  那部见鬼的电影怎么会大卖?
If everybody's so freaking smart, how come the movie did $675 million worldwide...
六亿七千五百万
...theatrical?
茱莉亚  医生
Julia. Doctor.
医生  快叫一个泰国人来接生
Doctor, you might wanna call the rice paddy now.
封锁出口  不准让人进出
Seal off the museum. Nobody in or out.
-拿来  拿来 　-快点  快点
- Bring... Bring it, bring it. - Quickly, quickly.
-让他坐下来 　-大家放松
- Sit her down. Sit her down. - Everybody just relax.
-你听得见吗?快说话 　-她没事
- Can you hear me? Talk to me. - She is fine. She is fine.
够了  我们走  不准再拍照
She's good? Okay, that's it. We're done here. No more pictures.
-谢谢你  布鲁斯 　-别担心
- Thank you, Bruce Willis. - Just don't worry.
-谢谢你  馆长 　-慢慢走
- Thank you, museum. We are code four. - Walk slowly, like you're doing.
我们会尽快送你上车
We'll get you into the car as fast as we can.
我们不要停  不要停
Okay, we're not stopping. Don't stop.
-你好 　-我们正要离开
- Hello. - We're on our way out.
我是伊莎贝  博物馆雇员  幸会了
Isabel Lahiri, I'm with the museum. It is so great to meet you.
-我们得赶快离开 　-我只耽搁一点时间
- We're very late. - I'm sorry, this won't take long.
我不想骚扰你  不过我男友是你的影迷
I don't wanna be an annoying fan, but my boyfriend is such a huge fan.
请你替他签名  可以吗?
I can't let you leave unless you sign something for him. Do you mind?
-这样不符规矩 　一下子就好
- That's very unorthodox. - Sorry, it won't take long.
-他叫什么?   -罗伯
- What's his name? - His name's Robert.
我以为你是左撇子
Aren't you a lefty? I thought you were a lefty.
她是左撇子
She is a lefty.
孕妇经常能左右开弓
Often pregnant women become ambidextrous.
你一定是个大影迷
You are a big fan.
她不一定会用左手签名
She doesn't necessarily have to sign lefty.
谢谢  太好了
Oh, thanks so much. This is great.
快走吧
Okay. We're on the move.
谢谢  保重了
Thank you. You take care, now.
还有一件事  我刚才跟玛西通过电话
And one more thing. I just got off the phone...
她安排你搭机到洛杉矶  一点钟要开会讨论...
...with someone called Marcy who put you on a plane from Taos, New Mexico to L. A...
《失眠小丑》这部电影
...where you have a 1:00 meeting about a film, Clowns Can't Sleep.
她要我转告你  大家都会迟到
Anyway, she just wanted me to let you know everyone's running a little late...
请你一点半再去就行
...and was wondering if you could make it at 1:30 instead.
我就知道
I knew it.
你真不要脸
Shame on you.
我们不认识  我是布鲁斯
I don't think we've met. Bruce.
我是伊莎贝  幸会
Isabel Lahiri. Nice to meet you.
你是真的有男友...
Do you really have a boyfriend?
还是在骗他们?
Or were you just...? Was that just part of the whole thing with them?
进行得如何?
So how'd it go?
你是拉希芮?
You Lahiri?
我是联邦调查局分局局长莫莉史塔
I'm Section Chief Molly Starr.
我跟欧洲刑警组织葛斯曼组长谈过
I spoke to a very nice man at Europol this morning, Commissioner Greisman.
他要你搭机回阿姆斯特丹
He wants you on the next flight to Amsterdam.
你的文件有一点问题
There seems to be some irregularity with your paperwork.
意大利语
那一个
That one.
先从那小子开始
Let's start with that one.
想像你在一个房间
Imagine yourself in a room...
低到你站不直  窄到你躺不平的房间
...that's too short for you to stand up in and not wide enough for you to lie down in.
没有灯  没有暖气
A room with no light, no heat...
石樯上有牙齿和指甲的抓痕
...and stone walls scratched by the teeth and nails of desperate men...
囚犯都被孤独逼疯
...men driven crazy by isolation.
只有老鼠与你作伴
You will have rats for company...
你只能从窗口看外面的世界
...and a small window that looks out on the world that has passed you by.
你父母有一天会老死  就跟你的梦想一样
Your parents will grow old and die, just like your dreams.
你朋友会遗忘你的名字  把你的故事当成他们的
Your friends will forget your name, tell your stories as their own...
因为当事人早已从世上消失
...because what good is a story when the person who owns it has vanished?
-你要什么?   -作证指控其他人...
- What do you want? - Testify against the others...
犯下赌场窃案
...in the Benedict case.
意大利的起诉会被撤销
The Italian charges will be dropped.
你们下午就被引度回美国
You and the others will be extradited to the U.S. This afternoon.
只要认罪  就能假释出狱
Plead, and you walk with parole.
办不到
I can't.
你再想想看  莱纳斯
Think about it, Linus.
我差点就忘了你的名宇
For a moment there, I was already forgetting your name.
等等
Wait.
请你等一下
Just hang on a sec.
莱纳斯
Linus.
谢了
Right. Thanks.
你还好吧?
You okay?
-我搞砸了跟松井的会面 　-松井?
- Well, I blew the meet with Matsui. - Matsui?
让我猜  他用"鸡同鸭讲"那一招耍你
Let me guess. He pulled a Lost in Translation on you.
他每次都用这招整新手
That's his idea of fun for first-timers.
-我怎么会那么笨?   -别自责
- I mean... How do I not see these things? - Don't get down on yourself.
-那太明显了 　-我们说过了
- Obvious. - We talked about this.
丹尼和罗斯一定很感激你  我也以你为荣
I hope Danny and Rusty appreciate the job you did in a tight jam. I am proud of you.
-谢了 　-我们都以你为荣
- Thanks. - We both are.
-你跟老爸说了?   -没办法
- You...? You told Dad? - I had to, sweetheart.
-你跟爸说了?   -我们在度假
- You told Dad? - We were on vacation.
对不起
I'm sorry.
这下可好了  他一定会拿这件事一直臭我
Great. Thanks. You're gonna be dining out on this one for months.
你老妈得大老远赶去罗马...
"Hey, remember the time your mom had to come to Rome... "
对不起
I'm sorry.
他每次都这样  真的很...
Every time with him. It's like...
真的很...
It's like a... It's like a...
这是罚你把我瞒在谷底
That was for keeping me in the dark. And that... That...
这是罚你逼我当神偷
...is for making me a master thief.
-这是罚你...  -好啦
- And that... - Okay.
毁了咱们的第二次三周年纪念
...is for ruining our second third anniversary.
好了吗?过来
Okay. Okay? Come here.
很抱歉我把你瞒在谷底
I'm sorry I kept you in the dark.
很抱歉我逼你当小偷
I'm sorry that I made you a thief.
-神偷 　-是神偷
- Master. - Master thief.
我也很抱歉  我毁了咱们的第二次三周年纪念
And I'm very sorry that I ruined our second third anniversary.
-满意吗?   -满意
- Okay? - Okay.
原谅我了?
You forgive me?
-一点吧 　-好吧
- A little. - All right.
布鲁斯威利这人怎样?
What was Bruce Willis like? Was he...?
跟上去  那是莱恩的车  跟上去
Follow it. That's Ryan's car. Follow that one.
等一下
Hey, wait, wait!
这是怎么回事?
What the hell is going on?
你爸并没有死
Your father's alive, Izzy.
你妈骗你的
Your mom lied to you...
不让你找他  他还活着 　你在说什么?
...to keep you from him. He's alive. - What are you talking about?
他们离婚后  她说他只要去找你... 她就会检举他
When they divorced, she told him if he contacted you, she'd go to the cops...
让他坐苦牢
...with everything to put him in jail.
你怎么知道?
How do you know that?
我干嘛相信你?我才不信
And why should I believe you? I don't believe you, okay?
你知道他在哪里?
You know where he is?
我知道有一个人知道
I know somebody who does.
你伪造文书  回不去了
There's nothing back there but a forged 1077.
法律顾问
帮我放进去
您的客人在阳台
客人?
什么客人?
-不会吧  真的?不会吧?   -不
- No. Really? No. - No.
那就太惨了
That'd be horrible.
对晚餐来说是蛮难的
It's hard, you know, for dinners.
你们一定很有一套
Well, you must have very good contacts.
通常要关好几天  才出得来
I hear it usually takes days to buy your way out.
-泰丝  这位是法兰斯瓦杜鲁 　-欧逊太太  幸会了
- Tess, this is Francis Toulour. - Madame Ocean, at last.
-你好 　-他是法国人
- Hello. - He's French.
你们不是应该去哪儿吗?
Shouldn't you be somewhere else by now, like...
像是外蒙古?
...Outer Mongolia, maybe?
我们去之前  想问你一个问题
Well, before we get to that, we just wanted to ask you one question.
-什么问题?   -你是怎么办到的?
- What is that? - How'd you do it?
你是为了这件事才来?
Oh, so that's why you came. You wanna know.
这也很正常
Well, I guess that's normal.
我有另一个条件
But I got another deal for you.
承认我是第一名  我就说出来
You both recognize that I'm the best, and I'll tell you my secret.
-是喔 　-这个嘛...
- Yeah. - That...
如果他先告诉我们... 他是怎么办到的
Make it if you get him to tell us...
我们就说他是最棒的 　喔  好
...and tell him that he is the best. - Oh, okay.
-这话我不说  因为你才是第一名 　-好哇  谢谢
- I won't tell him because you're the best. - All right. Thank you.
这样吧
All right.
你先说出来  我们就叫你第一名
We'll tell you you're the best after you tell us how you did it.
我怎么能拒绝一个人的遗愿?
How can I refuse a dying man's last request?
彩蛋在展览前的星期六傍晚6点45分被送到罗马
The egg arrived in Rome at 6:45 p. m. The Saturday before it went on display.
-晚上八点被送进博物馆 　-慢着
- It was at the museum by 8 p. m. - Wait a minute, hold on.
你当晚就下手?全馆封锁...
You stole it that evening? With the museum locked down?
你怎么进得去?你怎么躲过感测器?
How'd you get in the building? How'd you get past the sensors?
我的人怎么没看到你?
Why didn't my recon team see you?
-别碰我的东西 　-才没有
- Don't touch my thing. - I didn't touch your thing. Like it works.
你的手有油  你碰到了镜头  我什么都看不见了
You got greasy hands, you put them on the lens. Now I can't see.
-你什么都看不见 　-我看到你是个猪头
- You can't see anything. - I see you. You look like a retard.
你才是猪头
You look like a retard.
你一个月不说话  我给你一百万一个月喔
I'll pay you a million dollars if you don't speak for a month. One month.
-我要把你的头吃掉 　-来呀  我说真的  一百万
- I wanna eat your whole head. - Go ahead. A million dollars. No joke.
你连绳索装备都不用?
Right. With no equipment, no rope.
当然  别跟我说你不会
Of course. Come on, don't tell me you don't know how to do that.
你怎么穿过雷射防盗网的?
How did you get by the laser field in the Great Hall?
雷射防盗网
The laser fields. Well...
好吧  你是天下第一神偷
Okay. Toulour, you're the best.
谢了  丹尼
Well, thank you, Danny.
太好了  请你把钱拿来
Good. Now, if you can just get us our money...
我们就走人
...we'll be going.
钱?
The money?
什么钱?
What money?
我们赢了... 你答应还班奈狄的钱
The money that you agreed to pay Benedict if we won.
-期限就快到了 　-不  你搞错了吧?
- We're under a deadline. - No, no, no, you don't understand.
你没赢
You didn't win.
你输了  而且你们...
You lost. And not only did you lose...
全都被关进大牢  我也要老实跟你说...
...your entire crew got pinched. I gotta tell you something.
你跟她长得一点都不像  鼻子是有点像  可是耳朵
You don't look anything like her. Eventually, the nose, but the ears...
还有你走路打扮的模样
I mean, the way you walk and you dress...
这表示你们跟勒马克谈过
That means that you spoke to LeMarc.
你们去找过勒马克?
You spoke to LeMarc?
第二个星期四
只剩六天
既然我人都死了  这件事只有我们三个知道
Since I'm dead, I think my involvement in this should stay among the three of us.
-当然 　-没问题
- Of course. - Absolutely.
这真的很讽刺  我们的问题竟然要靠杜鲁解决
It's ironic that the solution to all of our problems will be provided by Toulour.
我同意我美国朋友说你们比他强  的确激怒了他
I'm sure I provoked him by agreeing with my American friend that you might be better.
抱歉我害你们惹上这么多麻烦
I apologize sincerely for the trouble I've caused you.
-你不用道歉 　-尤其是现在
- There's no need. - Especially now.
你们到他的别墅去见他  开始比赛之后
Remember, from the time you see Toulour at his villa and the challenge begins...
就要假设他会监视你们的行动
...you must assume he will have you under surveillance everywhere you go.
你们一定要演一场好戏
You'll have to put on a very elaborate show.
真正的彩蛋
The egg, the real egg...
有人会在早上九点半用背包把它从巴黎...
...will be carried in a backpack on a train leaving Gare du Nord...
北站带走 　谢谢你
...at 9:30 a. m. - Thank you.
你救了我们一命
You saved our lives, Gaspar.
这证明我还是比你们厉害
Yeah. And I'm still getting the better of you.
我偷了复制品?
And I stole a replica?
你的画放在米兰的仓库
Your paintings are in a high-security warehouse in Milan.
安德列欧迪街17号222室
It's 17 Via Andreotti, unit 222.
-密码是23116...  　-646  谢谢
- Security code is 2-3-1-1-6... - 6-4-6. Thank you.
你竟然连密码都知道
Listen, all games aside, that was... That was very good.
真厉害  你怎么知道?
That was good. How'd you do that?
我今晚讲一个故事就够了
Well, I told you one story tonight. I think that'll be enough. So now...
现在请你们... 请走吧
...if you, both of you, could please... Now.
-这是谁的房子?   -我在巴黎认识的一位小偷
- Whose house is this? - It belongs to a thief I know in Paris.
他认识我父亲?
He knows my father?
他比谁都了解他
Probably better than anyone.
他是谁?
Who is he?
-他帮我们搞定夜狐 　-他叫什么?
- He helped with the whole Night Fox thing. - What's his name?
我不知道他的真名
His real name? I don't know, actually.
我只知道他叫勒马克
I've only known him as LeMarc.
勒马克?
LeMarc?
天啊
Oh, my God.
你这些日子都在哪里?
Where the hell have you been?
我在等
Waiting.
等什么?
For what?
这一刻
For this.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
付给:泰瑞班奈狄1亿9千8百万
行了吗?
So we done?
没事了吧?
Issue closed?
-这不会跳票吧?   -不会啦  相信我
- Is it actually good? - It's good. Trust me.
我不相信你  也不相信欧逊  等支票兑现才算数
I don't trust you, and I don't trust Ocean. If it's good, we're done.
冤冤相报  对谁都没好处
These grudges, they're awful. Nobody wins.
这件事让丹尼受够了
Danny's had enough of this meshugaas.
小偷之间的竞争比我们还槽
And the competition, it's worse than our business.
总是有新人想要强出头
Always some new young punk trying to prove himself.
欧逊这种人不肯善罢干休  他们不喜欢输的感觉
Guys like Ocean, they keep coming back. They don't like to lose.
-自尊心太强  太爱面子了  -有些人会  丹尼不会
- Too much ego, too much pride. - Maybe for some guys, but not Danny.
你可以相信我  其实丹尼并不觉得他输了
Trust me on that. Danny don't feel like he lost in all this.
很难令人相信  不过这是真的
It's hard to believe, but that's how he feels.
如果他或是别人想乱来  我会等着他们
Well, if he tries anything... If anybody tries anything, I'll be waiting.
泰瑞  我不会算命
Terry, I can't predict the future.
我花大钱请的命理师都会算错
I pay professionals to do that, and even they get it wrong sometimes.
我不能保证没人会再抢你的钱
I can't say that nobody'll ever try to rob from you again.
不过我保证  万一你又吃了什么亏
But I can say this: Lf, God forbid, anything does happen to you...
绝不会是我们干的
...we will not be involved.
你最好说话算话  鲁本
You better not be, Reuben. You better not be.
星期一晚
嗨
Hey.
Good to see you guys.
嗨
你们记不记得  把我整得好惨?
You don't remember? You put me through hell, and you don't remember?
-嗨 　-嗨
- Hey. - Hey.
-你越来越美了 　-嗨
- You're more beautiful than ever. - Hey!
-505 　-405
- Five-oh-five? - Four-oh-five.
-谁在赢钱?  -我小赢
- Who's winning? - I'm little.
-你大赢 　-你是大?
- And you're big. - You're big?
我的天
Oh, my God.
-好的 　-我的天
- Hello. - Oh, my God.
你们被捕了
You're all under arrest.
你们全都是贼
You're thieves. You're crooks.
伊莎贝  李文斯顿戴尔
Isabel, Livingston Dell.
谢谢
Thank you.
是啊
伊莎贝泰丝
Isabel, Tess.
这是大人的桌子  那是小朋友坐的桌子?
The adult table. That's the kids' table.
-让我帮你 　-我要参一脚
- Let me clear that for you. - I'm in.
我可以再来一瓶啤酒吗?
Can I get another beer?
-我好像认识你 　-等等  我们还没下注
- I feel I know you. - Wait, wait. We didn't... We didn't bet.
你要五个?
You want five?
-五个 　-好狠啊
- Five. - So nasty.
好啊
Okay.
Is that a joke?
你就得这样搞
好啊
Yes.
-我的天啊 　-她喝醉了
- Jesus Christ. - She's drunk!
导演:史蒂文・索德伯格
编剧:乔治・诺尔菲
制片:杰瑞・韦恩崔
主演:乔治・克鲁尼
主演:布拉德・皮特
主演:马特・达蒙
主演:凯瑟琳・泽塔-琼斯
主演:安迪・加西亚
主演:唐其铎
主演:伯尼・麦克